<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>undeclared</title><description>Thoughts, stories and ideas.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.10</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 06:25:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>A Year in Review</title><description>&lt;p&gt;About a year ago, I posted this personal set of &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/blog/5-year-plan/"&gt;1-year/5-year goals&lt;/a&gt;. Looking back on the past year, I wanted to take the time to reflect where I am now along with some self-analysis with why that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, I've come to realize that this is honestly not&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/a-year-in-review/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">d0e41683-9d2b-457b-8a3a-9fb4d145e923</guid><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 06:22:06 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;About a year ago, I posted this personal set of &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/blog/5-year-plan/"&gt;1-year/5-year goals&lt;/a&gt;. Looking back on the past year, I wanted to take the time to reflect where I am now along with some self-analysis with why that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, I've come to realize that this is honestly not too unlike the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OKR"&gt;OKR framework&lt;/a&gt; that I've come to know after working at Mango. Shared attributes definitely include keeping these public (though I don't think publicly held goals necessarily need to be correlated with accountability) and leveraging a qualitative "objective" to provide direction. One important distinction, however, is an de-emphasis on the quantitative and "measurable" nature around these personal goals that allow room for me to take different ways of exploring a particular "objective."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After taking the time to complete this 1-year exercise, there's things I liked and disliked about this particular framework. Moving forwards, I definitely hope to do some more research in this area of personal development and take some of the learnings from this process to present a new set of personal goals for the coming year(s) - a topic for a future blog post to come!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="1yearplanfromlastyear"&gt;1 year Plan (from last year)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide on a track of CS to specialize in if I am accepted into a coterminal degree.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;This happened!&lt;/em&gt; However, I decided to add on a &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/blog/mse-masters/"&gt;second MS degree&lt;/a&gt; in Management Science &amp;amp; Engineering with the intention of coming back to finish a MS in CS if I need it in the future. The track that I ultimately decided that would be most interesting given my current interests is &lt;a href="https://cs.stanford.edu/degrees/mscs/specializations/#MIC"&gt;"mobile &amp;amp; internet computing"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in the healthtech sector, hopefully in some role as a data scientist
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;This ultimately happened through a series of project-based explorations in MED275B and BIOE391 where &lt;a href="http://davideng.me"&gt;David&lt;/a&gt; and I built a prototype to tackle denied medical claims using claims data and ML techniques.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would say, however, I'm grown more interested in influencing healthcare through the intersection of product + engineering rather than data + engineering.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a substantial mobile app
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I would qualify the contributions I made to &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.khanacademy.android&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Khan Academy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mango-health-medication-manager/id560657279?mt=8"&gt;Mango Health&lt;/a&gt; to be significant. I've also worked in close collaboration on mobile applications with 1-2 people ranging from an intelligent heart failure intervention agent to a bluetooth-enabled range of motion tracker for reconstructive knee sugery patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only app I've built end-to-end independently is &lt;a href="https://github.com/skleung/mobidx"&gt;MobiDX&lt;/a&gt;, a project spun out of work done in CS193P, which I've been meaning to polish up before publishing to the app store. In general though, I've found that I do my best work in teams with complementary skill-sets and don't feel like I necessarily need to independently build a standalone application to validate my skills as an engineer.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Android over the summer
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;This totally happened!&lt;/em&gt; And it came into great use during my short three weeks on the Android team at Mango. Some RxJava knowledge that I had from working from my time at Khan Academy even carried over to some of the API work I did with Mango.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise my fledging muscles in hard data analytics with a side project.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;This was not explored after moving away from a demonstrated interest in data analytics - there's definitely still an interest to be more analytically minded especially as I grow a more product-oriented skillset (plenty of analytics + event logging working in product development)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Really enjoy my senior year of college and immerse myself in the communities I'm a part of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was a resounding success.&lt;/em&gt; Two things I think contributed my sentiments here: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Switching from undergraduate -&gt; graduate status&lt;/strong&gt; to begin a &lt;a href="http://www-cs.stanford.edu/admissions/current-stanford-students/coterminal-program"&gt;coterminal degree&lt;/a&gt; actually reallocated up a significant amount of time away from class because of the 10-unit graduate tuition cap. I was able to then invest my time and energy into relationships, and the communities that I chose to continue being a part of. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intentionally not choosing more than 3 communities to focus on&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.ivstanford.org/"&gt;InterVarsity&lt;/a&gt; aka IV, &lt;a href="http://shift.stanford.edu"&gt;SHIFT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://casa.stanford.edu"&gt;Casa&lt;/a&gt;) provided a lot of freedom to freely enjoy senior year. Living in and staffing a Row House also provided a natural and refreshing opportunity to branch out beyond the foundation of friends I had built up over the years. I had the incredible blessing of being part of a dynamic and well-balanced row staff that not only put on consistently strong house programming but also became an invitation and outlet to engage more broadly with the larger senior year class.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thinking about this more, I think it's interesting to see how my senior year took a deliberate shift in priorities towards investing time specifically into the futures of the communities/organizations I was a part of. As an outgoing worship leader and a generally engaged senior year member of IV, part of my senior year was working with the existing and upcoming leaders of IV to prepare the incoming class of seniors and leaders to lead the community. The time I spent with our senior class in IV has had a rebound effect as well - a shared experience of leaving of a legacy brought our own class together to actively stay in touch and challenge one another in our growth as Christians. As for SHIFT, we entered the year with almost the entire leadership core in the same senior year class. So my co-founder, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/shannonxue"&gt;Shannon&lt;/a&gt;, and I spent a good chunk of our senior years fleshing out a roadmap and onboarding timeline and process to smoothly transition in the next generation of leaders in the group. I'm optimistic the group will continue to make important progress towards our goal of supporting healthcare innovation through an interdiscplinary perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build health++ (now &lt;a href="http://shift.stanford.edu"&gt;SHIFT&lt;/a&gt;) into something sustainable that will continue after I graduate
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Huge success here!&lt;/em&gt; I touched on this point in my last response, but I do think we're growing to be a formidable force and hub for healthcare innovation on campus and more broadly in the Bay Area as we bring together more thought leaders and resources &lt;a href="http://hackinghealth.stanford.edu"&gt;behind&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://treehacks.com/health"&gt;our&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://shift.stanford.edu"&gt;initiatives&lt;/a&gt;. I do think there's plenty of work to still be done as we continue to broaden the interdisciplinary lens of looking at healthcare beyond just tech + healthcare, but I hope to help the existing/future leaders flesh out that part of our vision as I continue to advise the growing group!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise more regularly and eat more healthily
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I think I have plenty of room to grow in the exercising domain. Though cooking regularly over the summer (in contrast to an on-campus meal plan) has definitely shifted my eating habits to be more healthy - having full control of the supply chain by buying a well-balanced set of ingredients has a strong trickle-down effect due to aligning financial incentives with eating habits.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id="5yearplan"&gt;5 year plan&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build something substantial with my skills and hopefully with a team that are more than just coworkers (whether it starting a company or a product within a small team @ a company)
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Thinking back, I think this goal stemmed from a personal desire to start a company with close friends. I think I'm leaving that as an option open to accomplish this goal but I do want to broaden the general sentiment here to include many paths to be "building something substantial" that doesn't necessarily involve building a company, per se, but includes building organizations or a network/community. Hopefully I'll have to time to flesh out what this goal is getting at in a follow-up blog post.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in a high-impact startup environment for at least a year
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;This is starting to come true as I continue to stay involved at Mango Health. I will say looking back that a year was sort of an arbitrary amount of time and characterizing what exactly constitutes a "startup" is also sort of undefined. I've realized that there are many different flavors of startups that come with different sizes, industries, and cultures. And though it's virtually impossible to experience all these flavors fully, it's my personal belief that the same amount of time leads to greater amounts of responsibility/impact at a company as the size decreases. Though the lifecycle for a return on investment (in terms of time) seems to decay the earlier/smaller a company is.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a well-balanced lifestyle that incorporates physical exercise, personal reflection, and learning from a diverse set of people
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;An ongoing goal :) Though this subtle but now acutely important note of "diversity" in perspective is playing a huge factor in the location/community I want to invest in after graduation.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start or finish a transition into another career (teacher, musician, executive, consultant, etc...)
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;This mainly stems from a lifestyle perspective that I've been interested in adopting inspired by a &lt;a href="http://web.stanford.edu/class/me104b/cgi-bin/"&gt;Designing Your Life&lt;/a&gt; lecture (given by &lt;a href="https://findinggodinsiliconvalley.com/dave-evans-silicon-valley-businessman-and-educator-finding-meaning-and-purpose/"&gt;Dave Evans&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/cs106a/tangents/tangent5.html"&gt;this 5-10 min talk&lt;/a&gt; that I used to give as a section leader (wish I kept the set of notes when presenting that thought...)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep close ties with family (maybe convince my brothers to come out to the west coast :)
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;working on this with my younger brother who's a current high school senior - though the college application is really an indeterministic process&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>What I learned from Mango Health</title><description>&lt;p&gt;As I wrap up the summer before my last quarter of school, I wanted to take the opportunity to reflect my first summer in San Francisco as a &lt;a href="http://kpcbfellows.com"&gt;KPCB Fellow&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="http://mangohealth.com"&gt;Mango Health&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/blog/why-mango"&gt;decided to join Mango this summer&lt;/a&gt;, I intentionally decided to join a smaller team to&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/what-i-learned-from-mango-health/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">73721900-b82e-43b6-92e5-be37a3aecde1</guid><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 05:17:25 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/images.mangohealth.com/website/mango-health-home.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/images.mangohealth.com/website/mango-health-home.jpg" alt="What I learned from Mango Health"&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I wrap up the summer before my last quarter of school, I wanted to take the opportunity to reflect my first summer in San Francisco as a &lt;a href="http://kpcbfellows.com"&gt;KPCB Fellow&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="http://mangohealth.com"&gt;Mango Health&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/blog/why-mango"&gt;decided to join Mango this summer&lt;/a&gt;, I intentionally decided to join a smaller team to take more responsibility and deliver more impact on the company and the users that ultimately used our product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="whatidid"&gt;What I did&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give an overview of the work I did at Mango:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A redesign + reimplementation of Mango's core search feature to add new medications (the first action a user takes after downloading the app) that ultimately increased the success of finding complicated medication names by 12%.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked closely with two other iOS engineers to implement an end-to-end feature for building healthy habits and refactored a large part of the existing code base to support the advent of both habits and medications.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spearheaded Mango's foray into an entire set of product features that would support new enterprise partnerships and lay the foundation for a deeper and fuller user experience.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generated market research and literature reviews to assess Mango's aptitude to move into two new adjacent spaces to complement the core user experience.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributed to the re-architected 2.0 version of Mango's Android app by redesigning data model hierarchies and fleshing out a good chunk of UI elements following consistent Android paradigms.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducted user interviews and fielded calls with clinical partners to build context for potential partnerships.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pushed forward a potential enterprise relationship that I'll continue to work on over the course of my fall quarter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id="responsibilitiesandimpact"&gt;Responsibilities and Impact&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I deeply appreciate the flexibility and freedom the team offered in filling the responsibilities of a role that didn't really exist when I joined. The feedback and guidance I received from the leadership in crafting and approaching new product features and partnership proposals provided the right balance between pointing me in the right direction and leaving me to figure out how to get there for myself. On the engineering side, working with an incredible &lt;a href="https://www.khanacademy.org/careers/interns/mobile-dev"&gt;Mobile! team&lt;/a&gt; at Khan Academy, set me up well for a smooth and natural integration into the iOS (and later the Android) team. I remember pushing production code by the end of my first day and contributing to feature development by Day Two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than anything else, the most inspiring part of working at Mango Health was being able to see the impact that my work had on actual patients. Sitting in on user interviews and hearing personal anecdotes of how our work was changing the very livelihoods and health of the people who use our product were invaluable parts of my time at Mango.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="learnings"&gt;Learnings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I'm taking away from the internship experience as a whole is a fuller understanding of the spectrum of skills that a product-oriented role at a company needs to have. Being able to actively work at the intersection of product + engineering was a unique opportunity that I had the responsibility of defining for myself in ways that added value to the company while giving me the chance to grow into unexplored areas of product management and product strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically at a company that has both consumer + enterprise angles, there's a myriad of internal and external pressures that drive the feature development and a product roadmap. In healthcare it's not always a straightforward process to align enterprise incentives with patient/user value. Conversations with enterprise partners requires a firm understanding of how Mango would fit into the ecosystem of patient care and ultimately meet the enterprise partner's core competencies and resources to create value for users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a user-centered technology company that scales through enterprise relationships, like Mango, product features that move forward need to answer the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it aligned with the overall company strategy?  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it lead to enterprise partnerships down the road? (This is perhaps a subset of #1, but this answer should touch on the potential for scaling to further enterprise relationships and the nature of those relationships.)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it add value to users?  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does it fit into the existing user experience and paradigms of user behavior?  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does it take to build it? (Answering this question should also consider whether features should necessarily be built in-house vs. in partnership with another team)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most important lesson, however, is one I'm still learning: how to ask for more ownership + responsibility in areas where opportunity for growth may not be clearly defined. Especially in a smaller organization where bandwidth for mentorship may be limited, I found that I had to often create opportunities to explore directions that Mango was interested in but not currently working on. This involved:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finding an intersection of personal and company interest  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;defining a role that developed skillsets and areas of personal growth and  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;outlining a course of action that indicated momentum while being open and ready for course adjustment. Ultimately, the set of responsibilities and tasks that I came to were refined over iterations of feedback and additional context of the space that Mango was working in. However, this self-driven process kicked off the most multi-faceted learning experience I've had to date outside of school itself, honing an ability to learn quickly in a broad and deep manner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id="kpcbfellowsprogram"&gt;KPCB Fellows Program&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the KPCB Fellows program to thank for opening up the opportunity to work and learn at Mango Health this summer. I would have no idea of Mango's existence if I hadn't applied to the program intentionally seeking a smaller team to work on. But the program was much more than an internship - it provided a network of equally driven and inspiring peers, opportunities + access to leaders in the industry, but most importantly, a community. Over our bus rides to South Bay, circuitous sailing around Angel Island, spontaneous hangouts, and planned programming, cursory conversations around work and school turned into discussions that defined what impact personally meant to each one of us. These conversations made me sure that my fellow Fellows will be the founders, leaders, and visionaries behind mission-oriented organizations of the future. Though the fellowship has ended, I’ve joined a family that is driven to make a meaningful difference on the world and feel simultaneously fortunate and responsible to be part of building and growing this shared vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A huge thank you goes out to the folks at Mango and Natalie/Justin/Andy for running the KPCB Fellows program - I'm excited to be returning back to Mango for a part-time basis in the fall and playing a part in growing the KPCB family for the next generation of fellows. &lt;br&gt;
Big thanks to Jonah, Alex, and Caitlin for reading over drafts of this blog post!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Mango Health?</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The past few months have truly been a whirlwind of decisions for the upcoming year and beyond. Since starting the search for full-time opportunities last September, deciding instead to &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/blog/mse-masters"&gt;finish a master's degree&lt;/a&gt;, and restarting the search for internships, I've decided to join &lt;a href="https://www.mangohealth.com"&gt;Mango Health&lt;/a&gt; as a KPCB fellow this&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/why-mango/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">f43697e7-e8ea-49d9-82dc-b3e96073fbfb</guid><category>tech</category><category>internship</category><category>mango health</category><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 21:27:21 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://i.vimeocdn.com/video/432704804_1280x720.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://i.vimeocdn.com/video/432704804_1280x720.jpg" alt="Why Mango Health?"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The past few months have truly been a whirlwind of decisions for the upcoming year and beyond. Since starting the search for full-time opportunities last September, deciding instead to &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/blog/mse-masters"&gt;finish a master's degree&lt;/a&gt;, and restarting the search for internships, I've decided to join &lt;a href="https://www.mangohealth.com"&gt;Mango Health&lt;/a&gt; as a KPCB fellow this coming summer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I've come to a decision, I've had some time to think about what I value in a career opportunity at this point in my life. I wanted to take this time to reflect and share what I've learned about myself and offer some reasons for choosing Mango that parallel a &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/blog/why-ka/"&gt;similar decision&lt;/a&gt; I came to last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="1scalingimpactinhealthcare"&gt;1. Scaling Impact in Healthcare&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a criteria that set the stage early for my search this summer. Before anything else, our quality of life depends on our well-being and I've always been interested in healthcare as a means to increase the bottom line for our collective well-being. Technology, to me, became a tool to scale this impact and I became uniquely drawn about the space of digital health over the past two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, there are quite a few digital health companies out there - so why Mango Health specifically? I was compelled by their mission to leverage technology to ultimately encourage more healthy lifestyles. They had a unique approach leveraging gamification that appealed to my interests in mobile technologies. Also, the team itself was a reflection of the leverage that initially drew me to digital health - a small team (&amp;lt; 20) working on a meaningful problem that affects millions of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="2productengineering"&gt;2. Product + Engineering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working at Khan Academy inspired me to think critically about product strategy at technology-based companies.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Why do we build what we build? How do we settle on prioritizing and rolling out product features? How does our product ultimately impact the users that use it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These questions ultimately inspired me to consider a degree in Management Science &amp;amp; Engineering (concentrating in Technology + Engineering Management), and I was looking for an opportunity to help me develop the intuition behind answer some of the above questions. As an engineer, I still wanted the opportunity to hone skills in building product, but I also wanted to explore this intersection of product + engineering - one that was more loosely defined and more open at the smaller companies that I was considering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mango was willing to take the risk of offering me an opportunity to dive deep into this intersection of product + engineering by investing in an intern that didn't necessarily know how to contribute in this particular way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="3thenonnegotiables"&gt;3. The non-negotiables&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most memorable interview experience that I had throughout this entire process was a question that Caitlin (Mango's VP of Ops) posed to me:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"What are your 5 non-negotiables?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This struck for two reasons: 1) it sparked an honest and intentional conversation about whether Mango Health could deliver on those non-negotiables 2) it inspired me to think critically about what I was looking for this coming summer and realize that a lot of these things weren't necessarily going to be directly handed to me - I had to ask and look for it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, this was a question that I had thought about despite not clearly articulating my reasons. However, the fact that Mango put just as much thought into this decision - what they could and could not deliver - gave me a good indication of how intentional they were about making sure they could offer me what I'm looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="4kpcbrockhealth"&gt;4. KPCB/RockHealth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's an exciting opportunity inherent in joining a small company backed by two venture capital firms I highly respect. In addition to having their vote of confidence in the team at Mango, they also provided unique opportunities to interns in their portfolio companies. The &lt;a href="http://kpcbfellows.com"&gt;KPCB fellowship&lt;/a&gt; and RockHealth's &lt;a href="https://rockhealth.com/meet-summer-digital-health-interns/"&gt;digital health programming&lt;/a&gt; were both compelling invitations to join communities full of like-minded people who care about making an impact with technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These communities were a distinct alternative to the "intern classes" I was used to at previous companies, but also an invitation to be directly "mentored by executives" while exploring a field that I've grown to be so excited about. (Having &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/aaronrossbrown"&gt;a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://web.stanford.edu/~cguan2/"&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-wang-93088533"&gt;friends&lt;/a&gt; that have vouched for the KPCB program didn't hurt either!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I'm incredibly excited about this next step in my journey and thank everyone who's supported me along the way!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>M.S. in MS&amp;E</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I was just admitted to the Master's Program in Management Science &amp;amp; Engineering on 3/4/2016! Some of you might be wondering why I'm pursuing a second graduate degree on top of a coterminal master's degree in Computer Science. Thankfully, I've already taken the time to write an&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/mse-masters/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">116fea62-81ce-4638-b65d-d27aae21a573</guid><category>MS&amp;E</category><category>entrepreneurship</category><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 23:55:28 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I was just admitted to the Master's Program in Management Science &amp;amp; Engineering on 3/4/2016! Some of you might be wondering why I'm pursuing a second graduate degree on top of a coterminal master's degree in Computer Science. Thankfully, I've already taken the time to write an entire statement of purpose to explain myself - check it out below if you're curious:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reasons for pursuing a second graduate degree in Management Science &amp;amp; Engineering are to build strengths as a product strategist and a leader of fast-moving organizations. Interested particularly in the concentrations for Technology and Engineering Management and Health Systems Modeling, I hope to train my ability to develop coherent strategies in the midst of uncertainty, and to lead technical teams that execute those strategies specifically at the intersection of healthcare and technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While studying computer science at Stanford, I’ve learned how to design, prototype, and build products. Now, I want to take a step back and ask bigger questions: what products to build, how products fit into the landscape, and when a product is ready for the market. Taking MS&amp;amp;E 270 has given me a good taste of what this process looks like for companies from a bird-eye’s view, but getting hands-on entrepreneurial experience by taking classes like MS&amp;amp;E 273 and MS&amp;amp;E 271 will give me tools to discover, realize, and then market ideas to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coursework and experiences as a former premedical student have given me a lasting appreciation of the medical field and a desire to make positive changes in our healthcare system. I would be especially interested in taking classes like MS&amp;amp;E 257 and MS&amp;amp;E 463 to identify high-impact needs in healthcare and train an intuition to address them with technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Across all of these classes, I’m especially curious to learn from other students in the MS&amp;amp;E department. Classes like MS&amp;amp;E 280 and MS&amp;amp;E 274, which center around case studies and peer-led discussions, allow the opportunity to learn from the collective knowledge of peers who share my passion for tackling and addressing compelling issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my time at Stanford, I’ve worked across education and healthcare on a legacy of projects and organizations that I’ve been fortunate to be a part of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Khan Academy, I learned how an ambitious mission can be tackled with well-defined products and well-scoped projects. During my summer tenure with the company, I designed and developed key features (i.e. offline infrastructure, featured content) from scratch to help just under a million students from all around the world access high-quality education. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building products with &lt;a href="http://muvrlabs.com"&gt;Muvr Labs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/olive"&gt;Olive Health&lt;/a&gt; gave me a chance to attempt defining and scoping products and projects at early-stage ventures. I built and iterated on MVPs through continuous cycles of feedback to product high-quality mobile applications that were a major part of obtaining seed funding. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In starting and directing &lt;a href="http://shift.stanford.edu"&gt;SHIFT&lt;/a&gt; (Stanford Health Innovations in Future Technologies) and TreeHacks Health, I’ve learned how to realize concrete steps from lofty vision statements. Through these organizations, I’m determined to leave a legacy of students empowered to tackle problems and explore innovations at the intersection of healthcare and technology. Through SHIFT, I’ve started a project fellowship that empowers interdisciplinary teams of students every quarter to actively explore innovative projects with industry and faculty sponsors. At TreeHacks Health, we’re bringing high-impact problems and needs in the healthcare and health sector to the most talented student developers, designers, and makers. Over just 36 hours, we hope to empower these teams with a warchest of technical resources spanning wearable devices to anonymized datasets. Beyond just the weekend of the hackathon, our vision is to inspire a generation of students to begin breaking down the barriers to a sector that deeply needs innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This quarter, I was accepted to MS&amp;amp;E 280, 271, and Steve Blank’s Lean Launchpad course with a team that is eagerly exploring market fit of a mobile-based microscopy application that can distinguish between bacterial and viral diseases. I continue to actively pursuing my interest in developing teams and products as a Course Assistant for CS194H (User Experience Design Project), a capstone course for the Human-Computer-Interaction curriculum in the Computer Science department. Outside of class, I also lead product development efforts to help a team of researchers from Sebastian Thrun’s lab consumerize Computer Vision technology that can recognize skin cancer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lessons learned from all these experiences have given me a vested interest in the MS&amp;amp;E program and an eager expectation of the value I could gain from an education in MS&amp;amp;E.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>My Urbana Experience</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Versions of the following testimony were shared at InterVarsity Large Group and at the Palo Alto Vineyard Church:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overarching theme at Urbana15 was "What story will you tell?" and this is my story from Urbana - one with two parts: &lt;br&gt;
1. Our God is a Global God &lt;br&gt;
2. Technology&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/urbana-testimony/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">8f7fc172-e171-4650-a3a9-fb17cc975c5e</guid><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 23:49:11 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://images.christianpost.com/full/57384/urbana.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://images.christianpost.com/full/57384/urbana.jpg" alt="My Urbana Experience"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Versions of the following testimony were shared at InterVarsity Large Group and at the Palo Alto Vineyard Church:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overarching theme at Urbana15 was "What story will you tell?" and this is my story from Urbana - one with two parts: &lt;br&gt;
1. Our God is a Global God &lt;br&gt;
2. Technology can be a part of God's Global mission!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking to the first point, the way I resonated with this most strongly was through the different styles of worship that we had throughout the conference. Each cultural background had its own amazing story and getting a chance to step into that and choose to see and understand the story of that group was amazing. We learned from the worship team how gospel music was shaped by shared experiences by African-Americans and how it's evolved over time through the era of slavery, Jim Crow, the Civil Rights Movement, and into the discussions of today's age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more than that, we began to hear pieces and stories from Christians from all around the world as we started to understand what the church looks like at a global scale. Extraordinary stories of persecution, of drastic lifestyle changes all contributed to the variety of experiences that make up God's global story. And we spent one night in particular praying and responding to the persecution of Christians in the most persecuted countries around the world. I think that night opened my eyes to a new sense of what it means to follow Christ. It shouldn't be a comfortable act that resides in the background. Instead, we should expect it to be risky and that actively choosing into it means surrending things in our lives we've grown comfortable with, and trusting in God's provision even in the most desperate of times. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second revelation I had at Urbana was through a track called &lt;a href="http://hack4missions.org"&gt;#hack4missions&lt;/a&gt;, where I came to realization that God's global mission can involve people passionate and interested in technology like myself! Over the course of #hack4missions, we explored projects ranging from redesigning dashboards for global health EMRs to hacking routers to distribute contentious material across the borders of some of the world's most dangerous countriers for Christians. It was here that I learned from the stories of those that have gone before that a career in technology and a heart for God's global kingdom does not have to be mutually exclusive and that there are, in fact, exciting ways to pursue a calling to use technology to spread the gospel and support relief efforts overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given how ubitiquous the hi-tech industry has become particularly at Stanford and the Bay Area, I challenge others to consider actively exploring ways to glorify God with the unique interests and skills that he's given us. For some of us, perhaps we are called to minister to those around us in our workplace, but if we expect following God to be risky - perhaps there are ways even Stanford-educated engineers can respond actively by stepping outside the comfortable, cushy lifestyles of a jobs in the Silicon Valley. I share this with you today, because the conviction I had during Urbana to explore this more intimately has led me to seriously reconsider my plans after graduating from my coterminal degree this coming fall. I'm not sure what the next concrete step looks like, but I have faith that God will continue guiding me in ways that will hopefully become clear to me in time...and that's why I give glory to God!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>#urbana15</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Over 5 days and 4 nights in St. Louis, I spent part of my Winter Break exploring what it means for me to be part of God's global mission. As a part of this missions conference that drew 16000 from all across the world, I participated in manuscript Bible Studies,&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/urbana15/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">a4853ae6-fe07-4f37-9c2a-3dae8c10fb49</guid><category>faith</category><category>urbana</category><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 01:23:53 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://www.hopcf.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/u15_facebook-cover-photo_general.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://www.hopcf.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/u15_facebook-cover-photo_general.jpg" alt="#urbana15"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over 5 days and 4 nights in St. Louis, I spent part of my Winter Break exploring what it means for me to be part of God's global mission. As a part of this missions conference that drew 16000 from all across the world, I participated in manuscript Bible Studies, heard speakers and testimonies calling us to action through the book of Matthew - the set of scriptures upon which the conference was founded on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are some of the raw thoughts I've had after each day. I also wanted to call to light one particular track of Urbana that explores what it means to use technology towards God's global mission. For the sake of continuity and compartmentalizing my thoughts, I will share more about &lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/urbana15/hack4missions.org"&gt;#hack4missions&lt;/a&gt; that  in a following post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="urbanaday1"&gt;Urbana Day 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arrived at Urbana, shocked by the scale that the conference was - the group of people that came expecting God grew larger and larger as I came closer to Urbana. 16,000 people coming together to explore our calling in God's global mission! The scale and magnitude of such an endeavor is something I've never been exposed to before, but how exciting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evening Session&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We heard from Dr. Patrick Fung, a missionary who became a Christian the same year he entered medical school. As he leads medically-minded missions today, he tells his story of obeying God's call. What stuck with me from that session is that "obedience requires immediacy." There should be no hesistation when we answer God's call but the question at the front of my mind was - "How can we be sure it's God?" Later as we shared in our roommate huddles to reflect on the day's lessons, my roommate shared his experience reading a book entitled "Just do something." An entirely different perspective that takes a more proactive stance on the way we follow God - perhaps it's not about whether we're doing the "right" thing so much as it is about doing it for the "right reason". And to us as Christians, that "right reason" is deciding on the next steps in our lives as students, professionals, and believers with an attitude of doing what we do for God's Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A social psychologist also shared with us the dangers of having an us-and-them mentality. We learned of a study by Keith Payne that demonstrated how people across all races and backgrounds misidentify a tool as a gun when paired sublimbly with a black face. She shared stories of her brother, studying at Yale's divinity school stopped by New Haven police for his skin color. We learned that these sorts of prejudcies CAN be overcome by actively recognizing them and choosing to act against them. And ultimately, it's on us to take steps to bring unity across the "us" groups that we're a part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="urbanaday2"&gt;Urbana Day 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morning Bible Study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew 8: Jesus came to save all of us - regardless of our status in society or however the world perceives us. We see this in the text as Jesus heals a leper, a centurion's servant, and Peter's mother-in-law. The passage reminds us that we cannot be born into the Kingdom of God but it is by great faith (like the Centurion's) that we can sit at the feast with Abraham, Issac, and David.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morning Session&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Fung shares how his own father denounced him as a son when he chose to go into Pakistan as a missionary. The deep-seated and rooted opposition that the father had against his son's choice of vocation and expression of faith led him to hold a long-standing grudge against his son. Dr. Fung shared one particular experience of how his father cared for him indirectly by telling him to finish a plate of roast duck - a story that resonated particularly for me as a Chinese-American as I was reminded for how familial care can sometimes happen indirectly through actions such as reminding a son to eat, through spending the time to cook and prepare a meal for another, etc...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evening Session&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow what a filling two hours of worship, testimonies, and calls to actions! We heard from Francis Chan who called us to lead lives of action not dampened by deliberating amongst ourselves but to actively go out and share the good news with all those who haven't heard it before. We heard from a missionary working in a dangerous part in the world right now who convicted me to realize that God holds authority even in the valley of the shadow of death. We heard from a worship leader and activist who called us to realize and understand our brothers in the #blacklivesmatter movement - to SEE and take their stories at full value. To support and stand alongside our brothers who share their stories of injustice, saying "I see you, I believe you, and I support you." I was personally compelled to be more than a bystander to this movement and take deliberate actions to align and identify with those that are suffering injusticies. Ultimately, it shouldn't just be about validating their stories as it is about fighting the power of hate that draws from the inequalities and prejudicies innate in our cultures and lifestyles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a beautiful feeling it is to worship alongside thousands of Christians all calling out to God - we sang in different languages to lift up a God that is global, transcending cultural + language barriers. We took a trip to black church to experience and understand the stories behind gospel music - what it stands for and how it's developed through the African-American journey throughout history. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="urbanaday3"&gt;Urbana Day 3&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morning Bible Study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We studied the parable of the landowners and the day workers from Matthew 20. Main takeaways from this morning were that we don't get to decide who is called by the landowner (representing the Kingdom of God). It's also not up to our metrics to compare the severity and amount of work we do against other people in God's Kingdom - the parable reveals that everyone who is called by God deserves a place and can benefit from God's generosity. The focus of this passage is not on the day laborers but rather on the character of the landowner and what the Kingdom of God is like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morning Session&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We heard from Dr. Fung again about what it means to be missional and why we can't borrow the spirituality of others. We studied the parable of the bridesmaids that brought and didn't bring oil for their lamps. He shared his own story of sending his daughter off to South Africa for missions - how he had to let go of his own reservations to let his daughter set out and build her own experience of faith and missions herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evening Session&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight was a truly powerful experience that brought global context to our family of followers - we heard extremely difficult stories of persecution from our brothers and sisters held captive in solitary confinement for their faith. This was by far the most challenging night for me personally as I struggled to understand and comprehend:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why, Lord? How can such suffering be a part of your will?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most striking in these stories of persecution was the conviction that the persecuted had to &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;care&lt;/em&gt; for their persecutors. They asked for prayer, not for just themselves but for their persecutors. I was floored that even in the midst of torturous suffering and stretches of unjust confinement and imprisonment, those that were persecuted chose to place love above all else. We learned of a man, despite threats against his life and the lives of his family, refusing to surrender the names and safety of his coworkers in faith - to trust in the Lord's power despite unimaginable suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, I was convicted to stop ignoring this side of Christianity - to realize and recognize the stories of those that truly risk their lives for their faith. We were called to &lt;em&gt;not turn away&lt;/em&gt;, to not turn the channel when a report of suffering breaks out, to not scroll past stories on our newsfeed that threaten the familiar comfort of facebook albums and status updates. Instead, we are called to raise up our brothers and sisters to bring their stories to light, to share them, and to support them in prayer and in spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the time that we had for reflection, I was reminded of Paul's words in Philipians 1, and wanted to share these words that I heard from the perspective of those that are persecuted for their faith.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I will continue to &lt;em&gt;rejoice&lt;/em&gt;, for I know that through your prayers and God’s provision of the Spirit of Jesus Christ what has happened to me will turn out for my deliverance. I eagerly expect and hope that I will in no way be ashamed, but will have sufficient courage so that now as always Christ will be exalted in my body, whether by life or by death. For to me, &lt;em&gt;to live is Christ and to die is gain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>What I learned at Khan Academy</title><description>&lt;p&gt;7 months ago, I stayed up reflecting on why I planned to &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/ka/"&gt;accept&lt;/a&gt; an internship at the Khan Academy. I articulated &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/blog/why-ka/"&gt;4 points&lt;/a&gt; that set Khan Academy apart for me and attracted me to the company that got a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kamens/status/560972531289423872"&gt;head nod&lt;/a&gt; from the fully-bearded-in-real-life &lt;a href="https://bjk5.com"&gt;Ben Kamens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/what-i-learned-at-khan-academy/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ae466645-0483-48b7-9dc8-771a4de2373b</guid><category>tech</category><category>internship</category><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 23:32:25 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://scontent-iad3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xfa1/t31.0-8/11823147_10153034752207215_8253802571512445911_o.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://scontent-iad3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xfa1/t31.0-8/11823147_10153034752207215_8253802571512445911_o.jpg" alt="What I learned at Khan Academy"&gt;&lt;p&gt;7 months ago, I stayed up reflecting on why I planned to &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/ka/"&gt;accept&lt;/a&gt; an internship at the Khan Academy. I articulated &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/blog/why-ka/"&gt;4 points&lt;/a&gt; that set Khan Academy apart for me and attracted me to the company that got a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kamens/status/560972531289423872"&gt;head nod&lt;/a&gt; from the fully-bearded-in-real-life &lt;a href="https://bjk5.com"&gt;Ben Kamens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of this summer, after 11 blazingly fast weeks as &lt;a href="https://www.khanacademy.org/about/our-interns"&gt;an intern&lt;/a&gt; - I wanted to share some thoughts on what I learned during my time Khan Academy and what I'll be taking away. &lt;br&gt;
If you're wondering what I actually did at Khan Academy, stay tuned for a feature blog post! &lt;br&gt;
 ^ hah! because I worked on new features :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="1youcanlearnanything"&gt;1. You can learn anything&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came into the summer with about two months worth of iOS experience and a little under two days of Android experience. On my very first day of the internship, I was presented with a conundrum: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join a relatively-new team working on launching a brand new Android product at the end of the summer with the caveat of personally knowing next to nothing about Android development.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join an existing iOS team working on a major reboot and update for the iOS platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/omgitsmgp"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;, my mentor, graciously gave me a day or two to really mull it over. I told Mike that my main objective this summer was to learn as much as I could about anything that anyone would be willing to teach me. With the opportunity to jump into an entirely new side of the mobile landscape, I made up my mind and took the plunge into the world of Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I'm so glad I took the leap. The experience gave me an entirely new skillset and a chance to contribute to a high-impact and unreleased product. I couldn't think of a better way to personally experience growth mindset, but I guess this attitude and mentality just &lt;a href="http://bjk5.com/post/57899463280/team-culture-for-free"&gt;"falls out"&lt;/a&gt; of the mission of Khan Academy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="2codeiscraft"&gt;2. Code is Craft&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fundamental tenet (and former title) of Mike’s in-progress book, I was taught this important lesson through my interactions with other engineers on the Android team. Throughout Stanford’s computer science curriculum, we've been consistently taught that code should be evaluated on a basis of 4x% functionality and x% style. Where functionality is evaluated on a &lt;em&gt;"Does it work on all cases?"&lt;/em&gt; basis and style is measured as a hodgepodge of high-level design, decomposition, and code clarity. Throughout my fledgling career as an engineer, I've been guilty of subscribing to transferring some of this logic over to a misguided opinion that the value of code is around 80% functionality and 20% style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming out of a summer of &lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/a/khanacademy.org/forge/for-developers/code-review-policy#TOC-What-makes-for-a-successful-code-review-"&gt;code reviews&lt;/a&gt; with some of the most thoughtful engineers I've ever had the pleasure of working with, I've learned that the reality of great engineering paints a vibrant and colorful world in contrast to the black-and-white 80/20% split. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By treating code as a creative product, I realize that style isn't so much an attribute of code as it is an element of the design process and approach to the original problem. When code is designed well, great functionality and style will sort of just "fall out" as a byproduct. Writing comprehensive test cases/plans, making digestible and incremental changes, and the liberal use of TODOs, doesn't fall neatly into the buckets of functionality or style but sets a codebase up for long-term stability and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="3digdeeper"&gt;3. Dig deeper&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the internship, this was one of the most salient pieces of advice that I took away and a life skill I'll continue to develop. Asking &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/5_Whys"&gt;why&lt;/a&gt; is a good first step to begin diagnosing the problem, but you can’t get to the root problem or misunderstanding until you’re willing to step out of your comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being uncomfortable with an explanation takes some getting used to, but it's a feeling that can be harnessed to push the boundaries of your comfort zone. Learning to tease out parts of a problem or concept that doesn't make complete sense is a powerful tool to dig deeper in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="onwards"&gt;Onwards!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm eternally grateful to the &lt;a href="https://www.khanacademy.org/about/the-team"&gt;team&lt;/a&gt; at Khan Academy to be part of such a inspiring and driven class of &lt;a href="https://www.khanacademy.org/about/our-interns"&gt;interns&lt;/a&gt;. If you're interested in providing a free, world-class education for anyone anywhere, working with a talented engineering team, or both, &lt;a href="https://www.khanacademy.org/careers/interns"&gt;apply&lt;/a&gt; for a Khan Academy Internship - they take interns year-round :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="http://hathix.com"&gt;Neel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/what-i-learned-at-khan-academy/ourracingthoughts.com"&gt;David&lt;/a&gt;, and Alexis for reading drafts of this. Credit to &lt;a href="http://michelleontheweb.com/"&gt;Michelle&lt;/a&gt; for the wonderful cover photo of post-it drawings of the Khan Academy team!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Projects Galore</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you're reading this, thank you for taking an extra click to view these links that haven't made it onto my main portfolio page. Each of these links showcases a technical project that was completed sometime after Summer 2014. I'm currently in the process or reimagining how exactly&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/projects-galore/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">d71533c8-962a-4240-a790-ab490568e499</guid><category>tech</category><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 08:28:42 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hi there,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you're reading this, thank you for taking an extra click to view these links that haven't made it onto my main portfolio page. Each of these links showcases a technical project that was completed sometime after Summer 2014. I'm currently in the process or reimagining how exactly to organize a repository for my work, but this seems like a pretty good place to start!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/projects-galore/"&gt;Cellscan.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Winter 2016]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently selected as one of 8 teams into Steve Blank's Lean Launchpad course. Our team will be working on market fit and rapidly iterating on prototypes for an idea we will be working on throughout Winter 2016!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://treehacks.com/health"&gt;TreeHacks Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Fall-Winter 2015-16]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lead a team of 6 currently building a vertical of &lt;a href="http://treehacks.com"&gt;TreeHacks&lt;/a&gt; that will allow student hackers to focus on and explore issues in health and healthcare. We've launched an &lt;a href="http://treehacks.com/iChallenge"&gt;Ideation Challenge&lt;/a&gt; to source needs and released our &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@hackwithtrees/our-vision-for-treehacks-health-d621c4990df3#.5k4aflhh7"&gt;vision statement&lt;/a&gt; as we continue to prepare for TreeHacks in Feburary 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://stanfordpython.github.io"&gt;CS92SI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
[Fall 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Co-instructed a class teaching the Python programming language at an introductory level. I wrote several assignments and labs for the class and facilitated grading and other administrative details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=clIbgkOTu2Y&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be"&gt;HOPE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
[Fall 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worked in a team of 5 over the course of &lt;a href="http://explorecourses.stanford.edu/search?view=catalog&amp;amp;filter-coursestatus-Active=on&amp;amp;q=MS%26E%20177:%20Engineering%20Innovation&amp;amp;academicYear=20142015"&gt;MS&amp;amp;E 177&lt;/a&gt; to brainstorm, needfind, prototype, and pitch a solution to the prompt: "How might we help former inmates become the individuals they hope to be?" Our final project presentation is &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1uoiJCwhtfR_rf_3dwdkxiGwcGFzlGSOK0uflsUprL80/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/skleung/robot-tag"&gt;Robot Tag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
[Fall 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working in a team of 2 for the &lt;a href="http://cs123.stanford.edu"&gt;CS123&lt;/a&gt; Final Project, I co-developed a finite state machine to direct a group of KR8 Robots to play the game of tag. We implemented basic localization, modeling, and path-finding to start the game and coordinated multiple threads to track time-based collision detection. The full project proposal is outlined &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/10NDQIDuJKg7EVmoWsYSH9SY_yqO5ppvAnbXTs-_rqb0/edit"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://devpost.com/software/impact-x0ldom"&gt;Impact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
[Fall 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built in 24 hours at &lt;a href="http://yhacks.org"&gt;YHacks&lt;/a&gt; - an Android application to empower people to go from &lt;em&gt;issues&lt;/em&gt; they care about to taking political &lt;em&gt;action&lt;/em&gt; on them by contacting their local legislators based on how they voted on particular issues. The app leveraged &lt;a href="https://github.com/square/retrofit"&gt;Retrofit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://fiscalnote.com"&gt;FiscalNote&lt;/a&gt;'s &lt;a href="https://fiscalnote.github.io/FiscalNote-API/internal"&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.olive.ai"&gt;Olive Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
[Summer 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed an MVP that leverages &lt;a href="https://wit.ai/"&gt;wit.ai&lt;/a&gt; to power an iOS client. &lt;a href="http://olive.ai/demo.mov"&gt;Demo here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://muvrlabs.com/"&gt;Muvr Labs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Summer 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built out and prototyped a mobile app that pairs with a hardware device on the knee for reconstructive knee surgery patients. The iOS app uses Parse for a Backend and the core bluetooth modules to connect with the hardware devices. &lt;br&gt;
(sorry nothing's public yet...demos to come...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/josephwandile/greylocknewco"&gt;Get Connected&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Summer 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hacked up an Ionic project that facilitates professional networking and helps people make notes of conversations and brings up interesting talking points in a timely manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/skleung/equations"&gt;Equations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Summer 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built an iOS port of a creative mathematics games that encourages players to think critically and broadly about mathematical design. See Github link for screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/khan/ka-player"&gt;Khan Academy Mobile Scratchpad Player&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Summer 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worked on an Ionic project to bring CS scratchpads to the mobile world for students! Open sourced on the Khan Academy Github page :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/lemonade512/KLSBadgeHack"&gt;Khan Lab School Barcode Scanner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Summer 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did some front-end work for this barcode scanner that facilitates attendance taking at the Khan Lab School.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/cs106a"&gt;CS106A TA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Summer 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taught a summer session of &lt;a href="http://cs106a.stanford.edu"&gt;CS 106A&lt;/a&gt;. You can see live snippets of the code we wrote together as a section at the link above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://vg-game.herokuapp.com"&gt;SentenceRacer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Spring 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built a gamification to collect full sentence annotation partly in collaboration with &lt;a href="http://visualgenome.org/"&gt;VisualGenome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also put together &lt;a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1508.07053"&gt;a paper&lt;/a&gt; describing our findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://conduitapp.me"&gt;Conduit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Spring 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deployed an app to help Electric Vehicle owners resolve charge rage by communicating more effectively which each other. Available onto the app store: &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/conduit-ev/id994322979?mt=8"&gt;App Store Page&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="http://conduit-blog.herokuapp.com"&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/natoparkway/PT"&gt;PT Helper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Spring 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app won Best iOS app in the course (described below) and $5k. The application virtualized the Physical Therapist + Patient experience through a daily workout routine complete with videos and detailed instructions. Also featured a physician facing interface to track patient progress and add more exercises/goals for the patients themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://codepath.com"&gt;CodePath Course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Spring 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was accepted into the first course that CodePath taught at Stanford to learn Swift and iOS in 6 weeks. Completed several assignments: &lt;a href="https://github.com/skleung/twitteroo"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/skleung/iOS-Yelp"&gt;Yelp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/skleung/CodePath-1"&gt;Rotten Tomatoes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/skleung/messenger"&gt;FB Messenger&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://visualgenome.org/"&gt;VisualGenome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Winter 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designed turker hits and performed a good deal of front-end work for the project. Also created the above landing page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quizzer&lt;/strong&gt; [Winter 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built a Java web application that allowed for quiz taking online. Received a 128% on the project due to additional features that were added for extra credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/cs106b/"&gt;CS106B TA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Winter 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taught a winter section of &lt;a href="http://cs106b.stanford.edu"&gt;CS 106B&lt;/a&gt;. Snippets of code we wrote that quarter is on the above website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/cs181w/"&gt;CS181W Final Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Winter 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gave a final presentation and created a website for our CS181W final project on Internet Vigilantism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://snappo.me/"&gt;Snappo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Winter 2015]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built an iOS wrapper app (really a node.js app) that's essentially YikYak for selfies. Finished under 48 hours at PennApps Winter 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://callback-newsfeed.herokuapp.com"&gt;Callback Newsfeed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Fall 2014]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designed the following &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1b0t4VVo3kPf8OyFlFHiNZSodF7NLrphiac7NBaqVIcI/edit"&gt;assignment&lt;/a&gt; for students in &lt;a href="http://callbackjs.me"&gt;CS 42&lt;/a&gt; (Contemporary JavaScript).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Project Exposure?</title><description>&lt;p&gt;It's my personal belief that technical companies should encourage their candidates to expose students to an actual project that a team is tackling before extending an offer to join that team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the candidate's side there is value in learning more about how the company works and a chance to&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/why-project-exposure/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">df30dad0-1f84-4dcd-a3a0-73a1eefaf7d0</guid><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 06:17:51 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It's my personal belief that technical companies should encourage their candidates to expose students to an actual project that a team is tackling before extending an offer to join that team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the candidate's side there is value in learning more about how the company works and a chance to get used to your potential collaborators. A fuller and more comprehensive decision can then be made after looking at the team, the codebase, and the way the company operates internally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the company's side, there's an upfront cost of an NDA and the intangible cost of draining current employees with a new hire that may ask questions. But the upsides in my opinion are huge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You're gaining a candidate who's is able to start meaningfully contributing to the team from the day he/she starts.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You're able to see how your candidate actualy works in a team setting (rather than indirectly asking about team experiences/projects).  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You hire a candidate who is making a well-informed and complete decision that apparently enjoys working with the team enough to commit to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id="parallels"&gt;Parallels&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This entire process is not unlike the rotations that grad students to through before settling into a lab. In the academic setting, the system encourages you to explore your interests outside of the binding commitment that the lab you rotate into is the one you'll spend the next 5-7 years working on your thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's only natural (and the norm in the academic community) to give graduate students the freedom to explore an academic setting that they'll potentially build the rest of their academic careers on. Why don't we open up the same opportunity for technical hires?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="whynot"&gt;Why not?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understandably, the risk on the company's end is losing precious time/energy  on-ramping a candidate that may not join the company in the end. But if the candidate is truly wants to work at this company, he/she will be putting their best foot forward. That's a great use of time for both sides here - the candidate gets meaningful work experience and an opportunity to put their best foot forward. In return, the company not only gains value from the work being done but also chances to iron out on-boarding and getting more eyes + perspectives on the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another counterargument is potential ramifications from allowing candidates to interact with the codebase and product before employment. But this shouldn't be more than a standard NDA that candidates sign before starting work. Given that these sorts of agreements have been part of the onsite process for some hiring procedures, I don't imagine that the friction here will be too large for employers to handle.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>1-year, 5-year Plan</title><description>&lt;p&gt;A long-term study into how my plans change over time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="1yearplan"&gt;1 year Plan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide on a track of CS to specialize in if I am accepted into a coterminal degree.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in the healthtech sector, hopefully in some role as a data scientist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a substantial mobile app &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Android&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/5-year-plan/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5cd0dd71-f2b7-48a8-8b87-174eec65d869</guid><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 17:23:57 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A long-term study into how my plans change over time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="1yearplan"&gt;1 year Plan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide on a track of CS to specialize in if I am accepted into a coterminal degree.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in the healthtech sector, hopefully in some role as a data scientist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a substantial mobile app &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Android over the summer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise my fledging muscles in hard data analytics with a side project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Really enjoy my senior year of college and immerse myself in the communities I'm a part of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build &lt;a href="http://healthplusplus.stanford.edu"&gt;health++&lt;/a&gt; into something sustainable that will continue after I graduate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise more regularly and eat more healthily&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="5yearplan"&gt;5 year plan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build something substantial with my skills and hopefully with a team that are more than just coworkers (whether it starting a company or a product within a small team @ a company)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in a high-impact startup environment for at least a year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a well-balanced lifestyle that incorporates physical exercise, personal reflection, and learning from a diverse set of people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start or finish a transition into another career (teacher, musician, executive, consultant, etc...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep close ties with family (maybe convince my brothers to come out to the west coast :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>CS 376</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a repository of thoughts and responses from the CS 376 readings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="6215"&gt;6/2/15:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;* Postcolonial Computing: A Lens on Design and Development&lt;/em&gt;* &lt;a href="http://www.dourish.com/publications/2010/chi2010-postcolonial.pdf"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This paper provides a refreshing and broad view that addresses HCI and design from a global perspective. Though lofty, the ideas presented here are necessary&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/cs-376/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cf4a89be-5d20-4039-be9c-593dc92bac15</guid><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 06:35:25 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is a repository of thoughts and responses from the CS 376 readings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="6215"&gt;6/2/15:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;* Postcolonial Computing: A Lens on Design and Development&lt;/em&gt;* &lt;a href="http://www.dourish.com/publications/2010/chi2010-postcolonial.pdf"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This paper provides a refreshing and broad view that addresses HCI and design from a global perspective. Though lofty, the ideas presented here are necessary for designing a digital universe for the masses. It's true that the world is growing more connected as the web has brought distant communities and individuals together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I particularly found the discussion of economic models very interesting. Especially in today's world the economic rift between different groups have become more and more apparently. Looking especially at Palo Alto and EPA, we see how economic incentives can play a role in the interfaces that different socioeconomic groups respond to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted to comment also on the point brought up by the paper on the topic of open-source software in Peru. I'm of the opinion that open-source software won't stimulate an economy. Valuable IP become the livelihood of small companies (especially start-ups) as they try to disrupt an industry. If corporations are forced to open-source their software, innovation is stifled and  new developments get captured first by larger corporations with more resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would argue that especially in a multifaceted and diverse community like Stanford's learning and teaching design in cross-cultural ways is even more important. I'm glad this reading is one of the later ones because it puts in perspective how broadly design can be defined and understood across many different groups of people. as designers, we're responsible to make sure that our works are cross-cultural and this work reminds us of that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yesterday’s tomorrows: notes on ubiquitous computing’s dominant vision&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1229069"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's sobering to realize that for the societies that benefit from ubiquitous computing, there are still a number of societies that sufer to even provide public wi-fi for their citizens. The article discusses disparities in third-world countries and I agree that steps can be taken to better level the technological disparities between third world countries and our first-world counterparts. More resources and attention towards fields like edTech and mHealth provides  avenues that the traditional tech student can get involved in making a difference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I agree with the paper's claim that we already live in a world of ubiquitous computing. I enjoyed the case studies that the paper presented of different cultures. It's interesting to note how the infrastructure that these foreign governments provide lead to the adoption of ubiquitous computing. I certainly think that the different perspectives that Korea and Singapore have on privacy probably played a conducive role in getting the public to adopt and approve of such infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The article claims that "messiness" is part of the inherent nature of such ubiquitous infrastructure. In the context of such large data sets and the complexities of today's massive networks, I can certainly see how this is the case. It certainly seems to be a misconception that the "ubiquitous world of computing" is expected to be without inefficiencies and starkly different from the world we live in today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, I am aligned with the author's claim that we are already living in it. Perhaps our bar for such a world is too high, but the affordances that we already have in today's devices are already evidence of such a world. Google's Nest and the Apple Watch all point to examples of connected devices that have brought us to a world where technology has started fade into the background of our day-to-day lives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="52615"&gt;5/26/15:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content-based Tools for Editing Audio Stories&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://vis.berkeley.edu/papers/audiostories/audiostories.pdf"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At a higher level, this study explores the utility of a tool to augment creativity. This is an interesting question because it involves a necessary definition of creativity and what changes when such a tool is applied. Do we become more creative when we're able to consider and assess many pieces and combinations? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the core of this question lies the motivation behind creating such tools like Photoshop and Garageband. When we're able to accelerate the process of creating, can we argue that we are more creative? Or simply more effective creators? I would have liked to see some more discussion of these questions in the paper, but perhaps we can bring this up in the class discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a system-based study, the technological overhead to combine results and functionality from multiple APIs and interfaces was an impressive feat. I know how hard syncing the timing of different threads can be especially from a web development standpoint. So I can appreciate the complexities involved in the multiple interactions required to edit and then resynthesize multiple tracks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Absent from this study was the process of needfinding that I would have expected from a system-based study. I'm also surprised that  researchers didn't show evidence of prototyping and building out different hypothesis that may have been part of their process in designing their final interface. In our CS376 project, the system we built involved multiple iterations and paper prototypes to arrive at the interface we eventually built out. I would have expected a publication-worthy system to present the same level of exploration and depth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let's Get Together (Formation and Success of Online Collaborations)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://burrsettles.com/pub/settles.chi13.pdf"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This paper presented some conclusions that were weakly tied to the data given. I felt that this study had potential to be data-driven but the authors fell short on designing a study that gave structured data. In particular, findings of &lt;em&gt;negative predictors&lt;/em&gt; was unfounded. It would have made their conclusions stronger to see some of the findings backed up by concrete data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think an  interesting parts of this study would be the social impact that collaborative songs have on the network itself. Unfortunately, the study didn't focus on this aspect. But I would have liked to see how collaborative pieces fared in the social currency of the network itself. For example, do collaborative songs end up being discussed more and by more people?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of the principles used in this paper have been executed in collaborative classes here at Stanford. In CS210, we use a "work-effort" to peer and self-evaluate our individual contributions and "effort" put into the group project. In CS147, we also incorporated peer reviews of team projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's my opinion that self-evaluation, especially in the context of a study, cannot be the most accurate. I think if the question was perhaps more indirectly posed, data might be better distributed to avoid biases in self-evaluation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="51915"&gt;5/19/15:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beyond Being There&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was not a huge fan of this paper. The conclusions and the hypotheses formed from the study weren't data-driven. In the end, it just felt like a lot of the paper was just talking about how the authors felt about certain lofty concepts. I would have felt their argument for abolishing the concept of "being there" to be stronger if it was backed by data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let me play the devil's advocate and attack the paper's fundamental argument. I argue that it is entirely necessary for telecommunications to focus its efforts on solving the "problem of distance." I claim that distance is a fundamentally broken part of communication that should be solved. If we can agree that the primary goal of communication is to exchange information and experience another's presence, I would argue that distance is the problem that keeps these goals from being accomplished when two people are not physically in the same location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This being said, I would argue that it is enough for telecommunications to try to virtualize and "imitate" the current and traditional ways of communications. Efforts to create a virtual reality and replicate the face-to-face interaction should be applauded and rewarded as solving an important and necessary problem of connecting our world. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, I'll make a case study about &lt;a href="http://slack.com"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; and why teams seem to use it so much. In line with this paper, Slack leverages the ability to form ephemeral interest groups through the premise of channels and private groups. By banding together people of similar interests with a common goal, Slack is able to accelerate the communication and funnel information in large teams to the right people. Beyond being there, the problem Slack is solving is to help the right people communicate quicker without the need of being in the same room.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Translucence&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.ics.uci.edu/~corps/phaseii/EricksonKellogg-SocialTranslucence-TOCHI.pdf"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Again, I'll play devil's advocate because I don't necessarily agree with the conclusions that this paper came to. I make the argument that providing information about people's activity presents more noise than signal. Wouldn't it be better if our decisions were motivated by objective, clear statements about what a system is doing rather than how users are interacting in a system? I'll support my argument with my own interpretations of current "social" systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, let's analyze  the effectiveness of Spotify's social network. I make the argument that Spotify's social network is not conducive to its main functionality of allowing users to listen to music. If we were to show my friends' activities on the site it would not add any value to my search for playing the music I'm looking for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I argue that other social networks that have networking and graphs of people as part of their mission statement are much more in line with this paper's argument. I'll cite Facebook as an example. With the mission of "Connecting everyone, everywhere," I argue that their social network is necessary to accomplishing their mission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps social systems don't always need to be translucent. I argue that it's perhaps more effective to have systems be partly opaque and then completely transparent if the user is intrigued in learning more of what's behind the opaque barrier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="51715"&gt;5/17/15:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information Needs in Collocated Software Development Teams&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/redmond/groups/hip/papers/ko2007bugfixing.pdf"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a software developer that's worked on different teams in the industry and through school projects, I can definitely say that a few aspects discussed in this paper differ depending on the environment you're in. Emphasis on good practices, code reviews, and consistent style in production-quality code streamlines some of the processes that are more of a problem in school. when projects are extended over large periods of time, the overhead to keep code consistent and organized is definitely worth it. It's also true that the industry standard of code requires collaboration given the cross-pollination from different teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back in 2007, I imagine GitHub wasn't the tool of choice for collaborative programming at the time. It would be interesting to revisit aspects of this study to see how much GitHub as a tool has impacted the way that programmers interact in teams. The way that GitHub organizes and presents information makes it easier for code reviews. In-line comments, commit messages, and the paradigm of reviewing and merging pull requests have become the industry standard of managing complex tasks. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The way the study describes getting blocked on issues have started to be addressed by common industry practices like Scrum and daily stand-ups. Systems like JIRA and even GitHub issues present ticketing interfaces that allow teams to track the progress of a blocked issue. I would think that a large subset of the problems faced in these issues would be addressed by modern systems like this and that the average frustration of the programmers would be lower. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wonder how accurate the self-reflection methods were in gathering genuine feedback about the different evaluation questions. In my opinion, some of their questions didn't really have a good scale on how one could rate the decision-making process. I also personally didn't resonate with some of the prompts (e.g. "What is statically related to this code?"). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emergent, Crowd-scale Programming Practice in the IDE &lt;a href="http://hci.stanford.edu/publications/2014/Codex/codex-paper.pdf"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was a fan of how this paper was able to provide valuable deliverables to the programming community. The frustrations and pain points felt by the novice Ruby programmer is definitely something I can relate with. In this sense, statistical linting makes a lot of sense. Sourcing and seeding well-defined and well-characterized idioms would definitely be a valuable tool and resource that would save a lot of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The paper presented crowdsourced review of the Ruby paradigms as the crowdsourced portion of the study. Arguably, the open-sourced repositories that the researchers sourced code from is perhaps an even larger and more elaborate fraction of crowdsourced knowledge. In the open-sourced community, the knowledge of more experienced programmers definitely trickles down the pecking order. There are also community managers that maintain the state of projects (e.g. Rails) who take great care to standardize and maintain consistency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think the paper probably left out a lot of the challenges they might have run into with the project. With the enormous 3M corpus that they were using, I'm certain they must have run into signal-to-noise ratio. I would have been interested in ways they tweaked their parser and logic to eliminate the noise to distill more defined datapoints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All in all, I'm in line with the paper's stance on closing the feedback loop between programmers and their own knowledge and style of programming. I agree that the idea between such an IDE would present ways to steepen and accelerate the learning curve for idiomatic languages like Ruby and Python. I think if the interface and feedback paradigm can be polished (think XCode's autocomplete features), programmers would really take to such a technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="5515"&gt;5/5/15:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sketching Interfaces like Krazy&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~garnet/silk-ieee-published.pdf"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do we prototype? Let me play devil's advocate for a bit. I'll argue that this depiction of the design process is too fixated on user testing and that users don't necessarily know what is most effective or conducive to the best interface. True innovation and perhaps the most influential designs comes from interfaces that toy with the border of what's familiar and what's non intuitive. Indeed, it was Ford who designed today's form of transportation that said &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"If I would have asked people what they wanted, they would've said faster horses."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;SILK claims to combine the best of paper sketches and the merits of electronic tools. However, it's not clear whether the automated recognition featured here in this system truly provides more facility to the production of well-designed sketches. I would argue that it would make more sense for designers to submit sketches and then specify which elements of their sketch should be interactive. For example sliders and buttons would be given independent axes of motion according to the designer's discretion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The description of the tool presented here belies a lot of interesting Computer Vision work that happens behind the scenes. The paper admits that recognition accuracy is low, but it's there's merit even in the elements that the computer was able to pick up. I would have liked to see more discussion on the training sets and the models that the researchers used to create its classifier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The paper claims that today's UI tools lead desigeners to fixate too much on the details of design. This leads to the paper's interesting investigation of how to design effectively for designers. If the goal of designers is to iterate quickly, then this tool is undeniably effective. However, if the goal of designers is to gather user feedback, this tool fails to cater to that aspect of design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voyant&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://web.engr.illinois.edu/~xu26/index_files/voyant.pdf"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wonder if this tool perhaps fixates on only specific types of feedback. Perhaps only the feedback that can be distilled in a text format is gathered. It might be more interesting to see what information can be extracted from more augmented aspects of user interaction. For example, tracking the eye itself as the user looks at a design (&lt;a href="http://static.aminer.org/pdf/PDF/000/405/553/designing_for_visual_influence_an_eye_tracking_study_of_the.pdf"&gt;Ward, 2003&lt;/a&gt;). Or other forms of feedback from the user's reaction that can't be framed in the context of text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The heatmap of salient points in the image suggests a lot of interesting next steps that combine computer vision and interaction design. For example, training an algorithm to recognize and build a classifier to recognize well-designed elements that draw user attention. Such a classifier then could be driven to recognize and build "well-designed" interfaces autonomously. Think &lt;a href="http://grid.io"&gt;grid.io&lt;/a&gt; for interfaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The way that Voyant collects feedback seems to parallelize the collection of feedback while the user is still processing the image. I wonder if feedback, specifically the gut instinct that people have, might be better collected if the user is forced to jot down first impressions after being flashed the image . The instant feedback loop, in my opinion, would be more conducive to receiving the split-second impressions of the design rather than the drawn-out duration of the user feedback that the current interface provides. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the case of interfaces built for specific types of users (say a grading interface for teachers), I imagine that there may be non-intuitive use cases and goals that the typical non-expert will not pick up on. The crowd in this study is derived from "non-experts" that may not understand the interface in context of the task that they have to complete. Because of this, I would argue the interface may need to either weigh "experts" more heavily in their feedback or create a better framework for helping users understand what context the interface should be used in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="42814"&gt;4/28/14:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Games with a Purpose&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~biglou/ieee-gwap.pdf"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Van Anh makes a strong argument for the value and motivation behind creating large, scalable interfaces that encourage collaboration behind a single task. I agree to a certain extent that this is valuable, but think there is a point where machine learning should take over. It's true that crowdsourced knowledge is a good basis for seeding and providing accurate annotations or descriptions that computers can not computationally derive from scratch. However, I claim large-scale problems shouldn't be solved by breaking them up into repetitive, individualized chunks - in this day and age, we should strive for equally scalable autonomous solutions that are built upon human knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gamification is a hard problem that always exposes a research project to risk. The first difficulty in reframing research problems as games involves ensuring that the resulting interfaces are guiding users to the same goal that the original research was trying to solve. The second is ensuring that the game attracts enough user interest as momentum to actually solve the original large-scale problem. Tension in balancing these two goals is a third complexity and it remains the researchers' responsibility to ensure that a sweet spot is hit for a game to be effective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The insight behind gamification involves analyzing existing incentive structures and trying to generalize or synthesize approaches in an attempt to solve a focused problem. Here, the authors are applying the phenomenon of ESP to the game they describe. In hindsight, it's clearer to see how users would gravitate to a game that seems to be dependent on a mysterious "psychic" ability. Furthermore, the implicit tension in anonymous collaboration provides a social tie to the stranger that is "working with you" to arrive at a solution. These motivations all belie the original task of image annotation which is the genius and the insight behind such a solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I argue that these insights are much harder to develop. We're facing a similar problem in developing an effective gamification for the &lt;a href="http://visualgenome.org"&gt;VisualGenome&lt;/a&gt; project. Though the basic premise of the problem involves sourcing annotations and creating "bounding boxes" around particular parts of the image. There is an unsolved hurdle of how to effectively motivate users to converge on a salient description of these bounded objects within the image - concerns based on accuracy, annotation salience, relevance, and redundancy must be addressed for such an idea to be effective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expert Crowdsourcing from Flash Teams&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://hci.stanford.edu/publications/2014/flashteams/flashteams-uist2014.pdf"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crowdsourcing is a powerful concept that has only recently been possible by the structures of online communities and open APIs that allow researchers and developers to hook into the power of the crowd. The application here to bring insights from organizational behavior research into an elastic and dynamic work task is promising. The idea that teams can focus and hone their productivity given a target timeline and work on-demand with a spontaneous team remains to be tested at scale. However, this paper provides an excellent overview into the system and a proof-of-concept example that describes their contribution to HCI well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two issues are left to be fully addressed in this paper. It's true that there's value in collaborating spontaneously to generate and iterate upon an idea. But it's clear that flash teams fail to bring continuity and consistency to a project. With such rapid and discontinuous results passed from team to team, I doubt that such a process would be successful in projects where domain experience and context is required. In other words, it's possible that the ramp-up time to get up to speed on the project overshadows the time that is saved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secondly, the overhead in facilitating handoffs is likely heavier in real-life and variable for different problems. Indeed, foundry provides a space and encourages effective workflow via continuous blocks and linked connections that represent input and output. However, these inputs and outputs are not well-defined for more non-technical projects that may revolved around market research or constructing business models that are dependent on effective handoff of information and insights that may not be well-formed in such a dynamic workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crowdsourcing is built on infrastructure that first incentives and then rewards workers for good work. I argue that existing structures like oDesk and Amazon Turk still fall short of effectively solving this innate problem. First, the incentive structure is still based on self-described skills and peer reviewed ratings. There's often a disconnect in the expectations of an employer and the perspectives of the employee in projects that fail to be addressed in the context of such an anonymous and online system. Unless there exists a more grounded medium of communicating clear guidelines and evaluation metrics, I suspect that projects communicated over such mediums will such an infrastructure will continue to fall short of expectations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="42614"&gt;4/26/14:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using social psychology to motivate contributions in online communities&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://repository.cmu.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1087&amp;amp;context=hcii"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This paper described a well-designed study that made great use of the experimental process in my opinion. The independent and dependent variables were clear and led to a distinct finding that the HCI community could benefit from. It's of my opinion that the study could have investigated one more control group to give a more distinct baseline to the results found. I would have liked to see the effects that just a single email had on the activity of the site. Devoid of any mention of motivation, it would be easier to track how effective an email message is itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This study didn't address one particular group of users that simply consume content. I would argue that the concept of social loafing only applies to active users that actually contribute to the community. In online communities like RottenTomatoes and Quora, a significant subset of their users make little to no contributions to the community. Here, a distinction needs to be made for users that only consume vs. users that actually contribute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building on this thought a little more, I think there exists ways to motivate people to make the transition from the consuming-only user to the regular contributor. If I were to use myself as a case study, it's effective for user motivation when an interface or a community uses users themselves to call others into action. Judging from my responses from a HealthTap email reminding me to complete my profile to a direct message request from a fellow Quoran, I certainly feel more indebted to my fellow user than the HealthTap script that generated that email reminder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Much as low-fidelity prototypes provide a low-cost way to test interface designs, these email interventions provide a low-cost way to test
  the impacts of manipulating relevant mental states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The paper recognizes this point, but it remains to be discussed how best to design interfaces that actually inspire such motivation in an online community. This, to me, is the real challenge. How can we design implicit reminders of uniqueness and value into the interface?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Anatomy of a Large-Scale &lt;em&gt;Social&lt;/em&gt; Search engine&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.ra.ethz.ch/CDstore/www2010/www/p431.pdf"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm a fan of this study and the concept behind Aardvark that spawned what seems to be a vibrant community and an acquisition by Google! Digging more deeply, we should wrestle with the question of whether this platform really is a search engine or a glorified IM interface. It's true that the algorithm involves searching to find the appropriate user to glean an answer, but this sort of social search isn't based on information but on the activities of a user. It seems to me that queries to such an engine must provide "heavier" requests to the server given all the tagging that needs to be done based on matching user activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user studies that they performed led to interesting insights about user participation and the satisfaction that users received after answering or receiving an answer. In particular, the experiment that the researchers performed in comparing Google and Aardvark led to an important distinction between the two in finding answers to subjective and objective questions. Though the paper attributes Aarvark's success in the subjective space due to the level of trust in another person, I wonder if trusting in a community such as the last paper would yield a more tapered response that normalizes extreme or biased answers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In comparison to such a search engine, we should consider such mediums of forums and content aggregator sites like Quora as alternatives to providing specialized information that has been crowdsourced in content and "quality". Forums and the Quora certainly have social elements as well, but in what ways are they different from Aardvark? I argue that there's value in the crowd to provide some fuller insights and value in also specializing and aggregating multiple responses in the same space, but it would be interesting to dig deeper into the pros and cons of all these interfaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The probabilistic analysis for this search engine is particularly fascinating, and I wonder if the authors ever attempted to model some of their calculations as a directed graph rather than a Baysian net (the authors call it a Social Graph, but I see no evidence of weighing the edges in their ananlysis). I would personally be really interested in seeing how the connections play out in the form of a social graph, and would love to see what weights features like "Chattiness Match" "Verbosity Match" all have on the graph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="42114"&gt;4/21/14:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Led class discussion following a lecture by &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stuart_Card"&gt;Stuart Card&lt;/a&gt; on the topics of :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding the Natural and Artificial Worlds (&lt;a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/sites/default/files/titles/content/9780262691918_sch_0001.pdf"&gt;Simon&lt;/a&gt;)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technology and Phenomena (&lt;a href="https://hcicourses.stanford.edu/courses/cs376/2015/readings/Arthur%20-%20Ch%203%20-%20Phenomena.pdf"&gt;Arthur&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1L53myX_eqBKKfC_WVTt7SjZueJcHH-lvWH8iABRzQkg/edit"&gt;discussion slides&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/u/1/d/1LcvSR1LBKcsavGNWqUxajT8-fLh_spA7VSRUBQc8GAE/edit?usp=drive_web"&gt;reading notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="41914"&gt;4/19/14:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cognitive Engineering Models&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www2.parc.com/istl/groups/uir/publications/items/UIR-1999-04-Pirolli-Handbook-Cognitive.pdf"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The paper provides a good abstract model of human interaction with a generic interface. The paper fits well its framework of a psychological study that analyzes and models a human processor. I like how the paper applied traditional psychological analyzes to the "machinery of human cognition" - it definitely read very closely with the way traditional psych literature analyzes human behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If this paper can analyze such tasks with such granuality in the context for humans, how would we compare to computers? I would imagine that computers can perform all of these "tasks" much more effectively and quickly. Does that make computers better workers than us? Is there value in the way humans can adapt to changing scenarios and edge cases that computers may not be able to?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In contrast to the other paper, this paper gives much more depth to its quantifiable measures. I appreciate the framework that the paper uses to describe the interactions humans take with interfaces. In particular, the granuality that the paper takes to build intuition behind a user's uncertainty model took multiple factors that I didn't consider into account ("equally probably alternatives", "information-informatic entropy", etc...).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pirolli measures task completition quite effectively, but doesn't provide much depth or analysis to more subjective tasks such as identifying what decision to make and how such a decision is engineered from the stimuli of the environment. I would have liked to see less details about GOMS models and more details about the decision tree that laid the foundation for such decisions. The paper acknowledges that as HCI tasks grow more complex, models may become incapable of describing the nuanced ways that stimuli is processed into an action. However, an attempt to address more of these nuanced and subjective behaviors would have been appreciated.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploring and Finding Information&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://hcicourses.stanford.edu/cs376/2014/readings/Exploring_and_Finding_Information.pdf"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm not convinced that shopping websites are the appropriate parallel to make given the author's focus on information + food-foraging parallels. Food as a resource is innately tied with a sense of the community/family a forager feels responsible to and the natural survival instinct; whereas, our shopping interests tend to be more individually tied and scoped within our personal preferences. E-commerce sites are much more with targeting/guiding customers towards specific products rather than the resource-rich wild that engender flight/fight responses. I would've felt like a navigation metaphor - the human ability to wayfind and journey across distant lands - to be a much better metaphor in this sense.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Though the study was limited by the technology of its time, two arguments point to why its findings may not apply to today’s interfaces. Visual elements like tabs, fixed “smart-tracking” navbars (i.e. scrollspy), navigation, etc… Secondly, mobile and web interfaces have been benefitting from the advent of Bayesian classifiers, and personalized big data, that improve the relevance of search results and next steps. That being said, text is still the primary medium through which information is conveyed and the study does provide relevant findings in that way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specifically, the study verified that the information sense curve shows the number of relevant documents decreasing at a slower rate as the user continued to find more relevant documents. Findings that suggested that users scan titles, appreciate relevance, and optimize their search for information, were not well quantified in their review. Additionally, there weren’t particularly practical or well-formed action items that the study seemed to suggest that would help designers and developers assist their users in getting the most value out of their interfaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I liked how specific the paper outlined the user flow for accomplishing specific tasks. The production rules fit in nicely with the framework that the model took with production memory. I would have appreciated more rigor in the way that the paper described weights and associations between chunks in memory. It would have definitely been interesting to investigate the paper’s discussion of a “spreading activation network” under the lens of a directed graph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="41414"&gt;4/14/14:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;inFORM&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://tmg-trackr.media.mit.edu:8020/SuperContainer/RawData/Papers/527-inFORM%20Dynamic%20Physical%20Affordances/Published/PDF"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a fascinating piece of work that almost doubles as an artistic statement. I'm impressed and greatly appreciate the clear efforts of the hardware specialists that made this study possible. I'm also a fan of the technical upper bounds (1.08 N/pin, 0.968 m/s downward speed) that defines a capped, but large space where the researchers could explore interactions. An interface such as this is certainly no small task, and I'm glad the researchers opted to include all the details from back to front that allows readers to really get a clear sense of what they built in addition to why they built it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The interface designed here combine the tactile, visual, and the actual 3D velocity (speed + direction) that the interface produces itself. This brings the number of variables to at least 7 in comparison to the color + x/y dimensions that we use on our phones. These additional variables contribute to an exponential growth of possible interactions. Forget swiping, pincing, and four-finger swipes, there are boundless unexplored forms of tactile affordances in this interface prompts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if we imagine if this interface was more granular? Let's do away with 900 pins and imagine 9,000,000. The applications for such technology in spaces like architecture, structural biology or even game design. Touch screens would turn into touch cubes that add all sorts of dimensionality to complex spaces that struggle with a 2D representation. Even learning physics from an interface would be incredibly insightful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The one thing that I found this paper lacking in is in the disconnect I felt between the paper's focus on "moving passive objects" and the connections such an interface could make to existing designs through visual means. It's clear that the wow factor of such an interface lies in the motion that it provides to these objects, but I had expected more connection between this work to the current interfaces that exist for now-visual tasks. The paper mentions issues with "jarring" its users with unexpected motion. Instead of trying to make these motions more smooth - why not incorporate the already understood visual affordances that our screens present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-Touch Systems that I Have Known and Loved&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.billbuxton.com/multitouchOverview.html"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I enjoyed the historic commentary that Buxton presents. The timeline provides definition to a framework and a context to understand the context of today's touch systems. Understanding where our interfaces come from definitely gives insights into what has worked before and why we've moved in the particular directions that we have. Though sites like &lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/cs-376/pttrns.com"&gt;pttn&lt;/a&gt; provide great depictions of our visual interfaces, I would love more discussions of our touch interfaces such as the commentary that Buxton provides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bi-Manual input in particular provided an interesting insight into parallelism. I took a brief skim over the paper that Buxton linked to understand how two-handed systems (think gear vs. steering wheels for our cars) can lead to more effective and parallizable interfaces for users. It's definitely understable how much more steep the learning curve is, but I argue that it's this sort of "steepness" that allows the knowledge and skill to stick as a habit. How easy is it to pick up driving again after months of inactivity?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I though the conceptual thought excercise present in Touchlight was really interesting. Though the link doesn't seem to be working, the work alludes to an interactive interface with high potential for extensibility. With multiple degrees of freedom in number of users, gestures, and even the visual representation, I would be really interested in seeing what visual and gesture affordances came out of that study and how we might be able to replicate them in the interfaces we have today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was a fan of the way that Buxton broke down all the variables that go into touch interfaces. It really got me thinking about how extensible our current touch interfaces really are. It's not immediately apparent the variables and points of data that our phone screens can synthesize to form a larger and more complex pictures, but Buxton's claim that "there's more to touch-sensing than contact and position" definitely deserves some deeper thought before designing the interfaces that we interact with on our phones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tangible Bits&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://web.media.mit.edu/~anjchang/ti01/ishii-chi97-tangbits.pdf"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This paper relates to a TED talk &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QgKCrGvShZs"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; that I saw a year ago that hacked Wii remotes to produce cheap, low-cost versions of interactive hardware discussed in this study. It prompts the thought of cost and availability - what if we can make technologies in this study as widespread and cost-effective as the Wii remote? Strip away the stigma we have around the remote in the way we hold and use it, and we have a functional input device with sense of space, direction, and speed. If we take these already functioning input devices and flip the mental model on its head to implement more ubitiquous ways to utilize Wii remotes, I would be interested to see how users respond at scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like that this study makes much more of a concerted effort to emphasize how it fits within the realm of ubitiquous computing. It's clear what ways features of the AmbientROOM "fade into the background" of ubitiquous computing. Though inconsistencies should be noted (e.g. "sounds of rain could be distracting"), the paper makes consistent observations within the realm of ubitiquos computing. The depths that the researchers go to to find appropriate metaphors to bridge the physical and digital worlds are exactly the channels that provide depth to ubitiquos computing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted to dig deeper on the point that the paper makes on "the ways ambient media can move naturally into the foreground." I find this statement somewhat conflicting to Mark Weiser's affirmation of the "invisible ideal." It's of my opinion that tangible items that prove to be too unfamiliar with the general public's mental models will inevitably cause an unnatural transition from the background to the foreground. Designing ideal bridges between the digital and physical, in my opinion, should keep the information in the passive background and not risk this unnatural transition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smart devices nowadays make more and more of an effort to blend into the background while constructing an ever more complex profile of the users they track. Given how widespread and inconspicuous these devices are, aren't they fitting into the paradigm of ubitiquos computing. I argue that these devices pose an effective counterargument to this paper's claim that tangible devices leads to a richer experience of the digital world. Devices don't necessarily need to be grasped or touched to provide a rich and even multisensory experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id="41214"&gt;4/12/14:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activity Sensing in the Wild&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.cs.umd.edu/~jonf/publications/Consolvo_ActivitySensingInTheWild-AFieldTrialOfUbiFitGarden_CHI2008.pdf"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This paper goes a long way to test user interaction in a new frame of mind that I assume the majority of users aren't used to. The paper describes of the commercial products with embedded sensors at the time, and it's clear that the majority of the products were not attempting to bridge the physical and mobile worlds very much at all. Linking all of the phone's infrastructure to the hardware sensors for 12 different prototypes was probably quite time-consuming, but it's clear that the focus of this paper is on the interface and the interactions that  people used to monitor their fitness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That being said, my main contintion of this paper was the lack of generalizability. I was under the impressiona that the sample size was too small and the responses too subjective to yield much insight into other interfaces particularly those without such sensors. It remains important to the focus of parhaps a product development team at car company, but not for research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another contention with this article involved the heavy use of "manually entered activities." This detail makes it hard to accurately gauge the use of the sensors when activities like cycling and other common physical activities such as sports. When the point of this system essentially reduces to a text-based entry, it's hard to understand the major insights that the interface claims for the sensor-focused interactivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Within the context of ubiquitous computing, early prototypes of today's wearable devices must have pushed the boundaries of what was possible. It's interesting to see however the main course of these fitness oriented devices turn towards smaller, wearable devices rather than the phone itself. I wonder if today's market would really take to the UbiFit system if it was incorporated into today's smartphone as a standalone device. Would we really react so positively or find it foreign in comparison to the other applications we use our phones for?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HydroSense:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.cs.umd.edu/~jonf/publications/Froehlich_HydroSense-InfrastructureMediatedSinglePointSensingOfWholeHomeWaterActivity_UbiComp2009.pdf"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This study provides an interesting, early view of the perception of "smarthomes" that today's Google Nest is pushing towards. The important distinction in this paper, however, is its emphasis in "single-point sensing" whereas the smarthomes of today definitely integrate multiple repository of data collection to form a cohesive story. I liked that the study was able to exhibit such accuracy to the true value of the amount of water used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much of the discussion involved analysis of the types of valve detection that felt irrelevant to the true nature of the paper. In my opinion, I thought the novel contribution to the conversation here was the way a user might react to such information of having these accurate measurements of water usage. I would have liked to see much less focus on the analysis of how the flow and the amount of water was calculated and much more discussion on the implications of such sensors and what directions this work could take in terms of integration into the home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I liked the level of granuality that the paper went into in discussing what the system did not do. The point that the authors made in discussing "partially-open valves" definitely proves relevant to the everyday user (like myself!) Furthermore the discussion of overlapping events arises a common everyday use of the bathroom when several devices are active at one time. This gives a good reflection of what the system is actually able to measure in the typical setting of water usage in a house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would have liked to see an additional study that extended upon this work to discover effective ways to present the information that &lt;em&gt;Hydrosense&lt;/em&gt; gathers back to the user. Given the Nest interfaces of today, it's clear that an effective smarthome involves a good deal of thought in designing an effective yet elegant interface that literally lives with the user. If we were to take this study one step further and build out ways to actually control water usage remotely - how might that effect our water usage? What implications might that have on our drought?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="4714designcreation"&gt;4/7/14: Design + Creation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting the Right Design and the Design Right&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.billbuxton.com/rightDesign.pdf"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This paper was an interesting, almost psychological study, on the nature of how diversity of perspective affects the perspective itself. I found the conclusions applicable to needfinding and prototyping research and an argument for a re-evaluation of the design-thinking process which seems to be focused on iterating on a single or main development track of a project. I think that the study was well-done in terms of the scope and the methods that were used to assess the hypothesis. It's nice to see paper prototyping as a vehicle to speed not only product development but to hasten research costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was personally surprised by the contention to the last hypothesis as I initially agreed with the claim that creativity would be more likely in the scenario with multiple designs. I think that the conclusions that the study came to surrounding making suggestions makes sense, though I am skeptical of whether participants simply felt less primed to suggest chances for fear of being 'too unoriginal' as they're surrounded by multiple renditions of a single design. If we imagine the setting of a discussion setting filled with students of different perspectives, I know from personal experience how I feel better equipped to think of discussion points via synthesis and reimagination of what I've already heard. However, despite being better equipped, there is a higher fear of making an "unsignificant" or "unoriginal" remark based on the diversity of opinions around me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The discussion about choice and decisions reminds me of an interesting point tied to choice paralysis as made popular by Barry Schwartz in "The Paradox of Choice" (and his &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/barry_schwartz_on_the_paradox_of_choice?language=en"&gt;TED talk&lt;/a&gt;). I wonder if these findings would hold after extrapolating the experiment to include more choices. I would expect that as the number of choices increases, behavior will be grow to be similar to that of the analysis of a single design. Interestingly enough, design thinking in general seems to push for quantity of ideas over quality - why doesn't this sort of process seem to suffer from choice paralysis?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Though this paper focused mainly on designs for user interfaces, I wonder if findings are relevant and applicable to other forms of design in the frameworks of art, musical composition, or even construction blueprints! What if we have experts or amateurs in the subjects take a similar approach to their design efforts? Would findings indicate a similar trend across the severity and variety of critiques? I would expect differences in subject areas like these to not show significant trends given the complexity of the critiques in these design settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Webzeitgeist: Design Mining the Web&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://hci.stanford.edu/publications/2013/Webzeitgeist/webzeitgeist.pdf"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I appreciate this paper's attention to isolate and focus on a specific research question, that of: "What can we learn from mining design from the web?" The insights here seem well abstracted from the noise of the web given the way that models were defined in terms of position, width, even to the granuality of the number of children elements. The definition of "vision" was particularly interesting, given that it focused on the most common color in the element and particularly paid special attention to edge pixels. Unfortunately, the paper didn't discuss major findings related to these more interesting features of "vision" which I feel is an integral part of design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The paper made a solid effort in breaking down the components of "design" into quantifiable and easily measurable qualities. However, I wish it explored more complex relations between different visual elements themselves. Specifically, how does the visual interaction between different visual elements on a webpage enhance or detract from the holistic design value of a page? Naive approaches towards this question might include overlap or dx or dy features in relation to the parent or sibling elements, and allowing standard learning algorithms like SARSA to try to predict important features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I personally enjoyed the amount of technical detail that the paper went into. I can see how others might argue that such attention to technical detail may be superfluous or irrelevant to the exploration of design principles. However, the type of mining that the authors attempted is definitely novel and clearly worthy of extensive discussion alone. In particular, the creation of Design Query Language provided some fascinating insights in how design features can be organized and summarized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would have also liked to see an analysis of popular pages - and see if correlation and design mining analysis across popular sites with heavy traffic can lead to the prediction of particular design features that foster "well-designed" features. Of course this venture would require a careful investigation in whether a "popular" site is comprable to a "well-designed" one. However, the investigation raises an interesting inquiry into whether good design conventions correlate with statistically signficant design features according to the design mining techniques presented in this paper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>BIOMEDIN 206</title><description>&lt;h2 id="informaticsinindustry"&gt;Informatics in Industry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A repository of notes from a seminar series in the School of Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="week8ibmresearch"&gt;Week 8 - IBM Research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Jianying Hu&lt;/strong&gt;, Distinguished Research Staff Member and Senior Manager, Health Informatics Research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IBM Research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IBM research has 12 labs globally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8/12 labs has healthcare related research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IBM&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/biomedin-206/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">54f0015d-c79e-4085-97f3-5637cbb523d3</guid><category>notes</category><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 19:39:31 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id="informaticsinindustry"&gt;Informatics in Industry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A repository of notes from a seminar series in the School of Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="week8ibmresearch"&gt;Week 8 - IBM Research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Jianying Hu&lt;/strong&gt;, Distinguished Research Staff Member and Senior Manager, Health Informatics Research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IBM Research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IBM research has 12 labs globally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8/12 labs has healthcare related research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IBM Watson Healthcare is a subdivision of the Watson research team to apply Watson's NLP to real-world problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data-Driven Research vs. Knowledge-Driven Research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge-driven research leverages Watson's NLP abilities to draw inferences from published literature, books, and guidelines
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Think crowd-sourced knowledge aggregating&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personalized decisions in Healthcare. Linking patient similarities to construct predictive models from longitudinal data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patient Similarity Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applying ML algorithms to automatically learn best metric from observational data and labels provided by experts. Training a &lt;a href="http://www.research.ibm.com/healthcare/projects_patientsimilarity.shtml"&gt;similarity matrix&lt;/a&gt; to find clinically similar patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Cases: 
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Identifying likely patients for Acute Hypotensive Episode - pulling out patients with similar trajectories to predict what might happen to the current patient. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patient CarePathFlow - visualizes care pathways and associated outcomes. virtualizes and scales the traditional way that physicians probe their own and their colleague's knowledge of what worked and what didn't.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CHF Predictive Modeling (NIH grant): Data-driven insights that found over 20k features with a novel feature selection algorithm.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temporal Event Pattern Mining - identify frequent patterns from the treatment on a particular group of patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network-based approach for combining patient and drug similarity
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Edges between patients represent similarity of patients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The patient-drug prior association to indicate how likely a drug might work on a patient.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PARAMO (Parallel Predictive Modeling Platform) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their deployment strategy is not unlike Palantir's they deploy engineers to integrate technologies into the client's database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to address sparsity/bias?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EMR Densification uses matrix decomposition &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EMR includes outpatient visits and primary care physicians (more comprehensive than just the bias in the hospitalization record)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="week7janssenresearch"&gt;Week 7 - Janssen Research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Ryan&lt;/strong&gt; - Head of the Epidemiology analytics group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cornell grad, Pfizer, Arizona Arthritis, GlaxoSmithKlin, OMOP (Operations Medical Outcome Partnership), UNC-PhD (Pharmaceutical Policy), Janssen/J&amp;amp;J, OHDSI, Columbia Faculty (Biomedical Informatics)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do we do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Janssen R&amp;amp;D is the research arm focused on pharmaceutical for Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We answer questions founded on observational data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where do we get data?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government resources (Medicare/Medicaid), insurance providers, EMR inpatient/outpatient data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Healthcare is like blind men and an elephant - datasets all have their own particular biases. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NO datasource is enough, we need to aggregate and distill answers from the different datasources that we have&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data pipeline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convert and structure data into schemas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETL design, implement, OMOP CDM, ETL test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;...ended up skipping this slide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evidence Sharing paradigms&lt;/strong&gt;
* Single study: write protocol, code, execute, evidence (publish paper)
* Real-time query: develop app, design query, submit job, gather evidence 
* Large-scale analytics: Develop app, execute, explore results  (making information more accessible to more people)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case study: Profiling diabetes treatment utilization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualizing who is taking these treatments, what treatments they're taking to determine who these treatments will be most effective for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What the future holds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patrick envisions a world that no longer is driven by single studies but rather by large-scale collaborative efforts (think: a massive grid that cross-references drugs and what effect they have) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="week6optumlabs"&gt;Week 6 - Optum Labs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Wallace&lt;/strong&gt; (MD) CMO, VP of Optum Labs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started off in Kaiser and led its integration with Epic's EMR system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do we create a learning healthcare system?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key Tenets:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Decision-making based on data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iteration/ongoing improvement of practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shared learning across providers, patients, networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patient-consumer centered and engaged&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dynamism and Complexity is assumed&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dynamic Change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We're data-gatherers (think hunter-gatherers) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can we create learning in other environments?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Value proposition in healthcare is changing: volume -&gt; value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can we get for-profit and non-profit entities to work on the same project?
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;e.g. Life sciences + delivery companies&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research -&gt; Clinical Translation -&gt; Innovation -&gt; Policy change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get systematic about innovation (e.g. Bell labs, Proctor &amp;amp; Gamble): make it reproducible, reliable, flexible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Architect systems that are not just technical but also social&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UnitedHealth and Optum&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UnitedHealth Group is the trading company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60 million in the US get benefits from UnitedHealthcare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optum drives $50B+ and employes 80,000 to provide health services in addition to the benefits that UnitedHealthcare provides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optum now has ~24 partners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data is deidentified (common hashing + salt across different services)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aggregates data that comes from clinical records and insurance claims&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Precision Medicine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much more than just personalized genomics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started out as just trying to better understand heart disease and heart failure cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optum provides a commons where different groups can work on a problem with the same data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What about &lt;strong&gt;deep phenotyping&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Can we identify people that would benefit more from different &lt;em&gt;types&lt;/em&gt; of delivery rather&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's not just a medical problem, we need to include more than just the data about the body but their environments as well (i.e. improved prognosis from wife that cooks rather than living alone)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"n of 1" &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decision support: when a doctor sees a patient in a population like the patient and knows what has worked well in the population or community 
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Can we create an amazon-like service that caters to this?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much do we waste in healthcare?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30%&lt;/strong&gt; is wasted (doesn't benefit the patient)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Categories: Unnecessary services, inefficiently delivered services, prices that are too high, excessive administrative, fraud, missed prevention opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"pay-go" structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="week5dnanexus"&gt;Week 5 - DNAnexus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Asimenos&lt;/strong&gt; (PhD) - Director of Science at DNAnexus, EE undergrad (from Greece), '09 PhD in CS. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joined startup started by his advisor after looking for post-docs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Role model was &lt;a href="http://www.jcvi.org/cms/about/bios/jcventer/?em_x=22"&gt;Craig Venter&lt;/a&gt;, was interested why he was always one step of other people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crazy idea:&lt;/strong&gt; if we can get blood from a crime scene an construct a genetic profile of the suspect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Powers of ten - a ten-fold magnification into the DNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked on ENCODE project while at Stanford&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genetics Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mapping&lt;/strong&gt; - comparing chunks of the genome to see what parts are identical and what bases have been mutated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variation Calling&lt;/strong&gt; - creates a file with variants that details where the current genome has deviated from a reference genome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DNAnexus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Funded by &lt;strong&gt;Google Ventures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computation happens dynamically and elastically - computers are spun up on the spot to handle computation (sounds like AWS for genomes...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global and collaborative - their code is also only for developers and researchers to collaborate all over the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demo: showed us a cloud-based data analytics platform to manage DNA sequence data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their software interfaces and creates a secure network between R&amp;amp;D departments + clinical centers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key distinguishing factors: doesn't focus on the analytical techniques (these are all open source), compliant for regulatory practices for data on the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They estimate that &lt;strong&gt;1/3&lt;/strong&gt; of all the sequencing that has happened has touched DNAnexus. They're currently branching out to China in collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you guys have competitors?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;They started in 2009, early mover on the cloud and there's nobody competing with them at their scale. Smaller companies focus on filling in the niche needs of organizations with smaller needs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does your R&amp;amp;D focus on?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Has some R&amp;amp;D focused on developing query tools to make it easier for researchers to download only the relevant genomes they need&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How customizable is the pipeline?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;"Bring your own code" for your own customizable analyses. DNAnexus stresses that their platform is meant for large-scale data analysis. You can take their output and give to intelligent services like &lt;a href="http://www.stationxinc.com/#introducing-genepool"&gt;StationX&lt;/a&gt; to make predictions from the data.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are you guys secure?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;They use layers of security on top of AWS. Didn't elaborate the specifics of what layers these are, but he talked about how quickly they had to patch up vulnerabilities from HeartBleed&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who initiates this process (chicken or the egg)?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;More common case is the pharma companies who ask their vendors to get onboard DNAnexus.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garvan Institute&lt;/strong&gt; (DNAnexus client)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Illumina - announced sequencing for $1000/genome for a machine for $10 million machine (HiSeq X Ten)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garvan was first purchaser of the Illumina HiSeq X Ten.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clinical Diagnostics - using the instrument to create actionable findings from DNA. Still at a very early stage, but holds potential to be very life changing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.regeneron.com/"&gt;Regeneron&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (DNAnexus client)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pharmaceutical company from Tarrytown, NY&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George D. Yancopoulo, Chief Scientific Office, launched the largest sequencing effort to sequence the genomes of these people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborating with Geisinger - a healthcare provider from Pennsylvania with very well-curated EMR records. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PCSK9 - mutation in this gene leads to low cholesterol &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developed a drug (clinical trial stage 3) attacking this gene to lower cholesterol. &lt;a href="http://www.fiercebiotech.com/story/sanofi-regeneron-capture-shot-first-mover-advantage-pcsk9-market/2015-01-26"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On track to sequence 80,000 exomes this year. This puts them at 250,000 people sequenced in total&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="week4wearablesdataandplumbing"&gt;Week 4 - Wearables, Data, and Plumbing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rachel Kalmar&lt;/strong&gt; (PhD) - Physics Undergrad @UCSB Neuroscience PhD @Stanford. Formally of Misfit Wearables,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Came to Stanford interested in Neuroscience and research didn't pan out, but a project at a Hackathon did! Her team got into RockHealth incubator program and got a crash course in entrepreneurship with an open-source integration platform that started off as an Arduino on a t-shirt&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sometimes data is too hard to clean - you need to fix the plumbing that the data comes from&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Big problems: Bad Data, Time is hard (hard to get time variances right - how do you sanitize input effectively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time is Hard
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;standardized time isn't even that old - we only needed it when cities started centralizing people from towns that were on their own time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this is where we are with wearables now - everything is in their own time zones&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"OnStar" for the body - early detection of disease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closing feedback loop - smart navigation for our health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the 3 biggest challenges in wearables:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery Life&lt;/strong&gt;. Everything is a tradeoff with battery life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standards&lt;/strong&gt; - none of our devices are really speaking the same language. Most are using low-level bluetooth. It's still not possible to compare stuff like "steps" across different devices or across different activities. (ActivityScore, NikeFuel, etc...)
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why not? We're still prototyping and it's still too soon for standards.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data sharing&lt;/strong&gt;- how do we make it easier to share data. Is it fear of getting scooped, inability to reproduce findings, platform differences?
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;ResearchKit. Allowing phone to be used as a data collection tool.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="week3googlexbaselinestudy"&gt;Week 3 - Google[x] Baseline study&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vikram Bajaj&lt;/strong&gt; (PhD) - initially classics @UPenn (Undergrad) + MIT (Grad)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faculty at Berkeley and then 2 startups, now at Google[x]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comes from spectroscopy background (NMR)
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Functional MRI: noninvasive spectroscopic techniques to see structure + dynamic view of function &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vision evolved from proton gradient as a signaling mechanism (rather than an energy-generating mechnaism)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biomimetic nanoparticle probes for imaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SkinScan: targeting cosmetic dermatology - wounding and the healing skin. 
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;handheld device to detect types of skin filler (the part that heals)  &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chevron startup: Oil well logging - building MRI spectrometers that work from inside out to oil well drills to tell you information about the oil around the drill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id="whatshappeningatgooglex"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's happening at Google[x]?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intersection of: 
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Huge Problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radical Solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breakthrough Technology&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not to be too afraid of failure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"It's hard to think of making something 10x better" but this is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; in healthcare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Problems:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Self-driving cars - leading causes of death. Replacing drivers to make 10x improvement in solving this problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Medical Tri-corder" - diagnostics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Baseline Study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id="baselinestudy"&gt;Baseline Study&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disease pathology: traditionally HE Stain (Hematoxylin and eosin stain) but moving towards "molecular markers" and quantative analyses of biological pathways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cancer is not one disease, but hetrogeneous in profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More data beats better algorithms - we learn from the quality of the data and the parts that we pick out to be significant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limits of big data: 
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;1854 Soho Cholera outbreak. Big data detected the cause of the outbreak. But removing the cause doesn't tell you anything about the disease or lead to any mechanistic insights.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="week2gingeriobehavioralanalyticsforhealthcare"&gt;Week 2 - Ginger.io: behavioral Analytics for Healthcare&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gourab De&lt;/strong&gt; (PhD) - biostatistics + Machine Learning. Expert in Risk &amp;amp; Outcomes modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health economics - somone in paying for hospitalization. If you reduce hospitalization, you're saving costs overall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Idea:&lt;/strong&gt; Making data more granular in the time between visits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right now doctors are only getting a glimpse (or a snapchat) of patients from visit to visit. Doctors are at a loss to learn from the time between visits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ginger.io provides: Continuous cycle for engagement, feedback and measurement: passive data, in-app surveys. Analyzing behavior, enable interventions -&gt; measuring outcomes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrating provided data with patient data from hospitals
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Virtual silos are used to merge and hold information from the app and the current hospital infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cannot integrate with EMR&lt;/strong&gt; (this is a very hard problem from a privacy perspective and who owns the data)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insights from ginger.io data&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helped uncover a pattern between stress at home + low mobility.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A patient caring for two mentally unstable children improved from higher mobility&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's next for Sensor Data + Modeling in Healthcare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smartphone and wearables have gone mainstream: 58% of US population owns smartphones. 76% of clinicians think health apps would be helpful for patientswith chronic conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Major players entering space - Apple/HealthKit/ResearchKit etc...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Independent Research Proposal</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a proposal for 4 units of independent study under Stanford's CS199 system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've wanted to learn iOS programming for a long time but haven't had the opportunity due to only recently getting a Macbook and not having time last quarter for CS193P. This quarter I was accepted&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/independent-research-proposal/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">0b6fe39f-1858-42e2-a17c-f0d094a9bd0a</guid><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 17:29:36 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is a proposal for 4 units of independent study under Stanford's CS199 system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've wanted to learn iOS programming for a long time but haven't had the opportunity due to only recently getting a Macbook and not having time last quarter for CS193P. This quarter I was accepted into CodePath's Swift bootcamp to have an accelerated introduction and crash course into iOS and Swift programming. The course expects a 10-12 hour commitment a week that includes live coding in lecture and a substanatial amount of work outside the lectures themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to iOS programming, I also want to extend my capacities as a full-stack engineer - particularly with advanced web APIs and more complex front-end frameworks. This additional goal is to supplant the earlier part of the quarter where the CodePath course will be redundant to parts of iOS programming I've already become familiar with through tutorials and the first two weeks of CS193P.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To obtain breadth in using more complicated web APIs and frameworks (namely Twilio and Facebook's Parse + React)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To complete a substantial project in Swift while following CodePath's course at Stanford to do so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proposed Schedule for the Quarter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week 1 - 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Integrating advanced web APIs with lightweight applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Takeaway:&lt;/em&gt; A text-based application for residents to play Assasins. Twilio API for the texting interface and a Parse database to store the order + status of players in the game. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Skills:&lt;/em&gt; Twilio API, Facebook Parse database, deploying non-web-based application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weeks 3-5:&lt;/strong&gt; Smaller based Swift applications built from CodePath's cirriculum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Takeaway(s):&lt;/em&gt; Clones of Yelp, Twitter, and Rotten Tomatoes, etc... &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Skills:&lt;/em&gt; Storyboarding, UI elements, navigation elements, networking + application layer, View controllers etc...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weeks 6-10:&lt;/strong&gt; Group capstone project as a culmination of the CodePath cirriculum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Takeaway:&lt;/em&gt; Complex application possibly including: Soundcloud downloading app, Video clipping and looping for GIFs.
&lt;em&gt;Skills:&lt;/em&gt; Working in a team setting, coordinating to develop elements in parallel, etc...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commitments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will hold myself to demonstrating some benchmark or progress that I will set the week prior. I will also keep a weekly record detailing the skills learned that week and what I built with what I learned. Benchmarks and progress will be documented simultaneously through a shared Google Document and links to Github repos of the code written that week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In return, I ask if we could schedule 15-30 minute meetings every week to check up on progress and for feedback on what's been created so far.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>5 Learnings + Unlearnings</title><description>&lt;p&gt;We were charged with writing 5 "learnings and unlearnings" from our experiences in the course. I wanted to share my takeaways from the class and summarize them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reframing&lt;/strong&gt;: This was probably one of the most valuable tools I took away from the course. I've found a lot of value&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/5-learnings-unlearnings/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">698f56bf-5ce7-4404-a2f5-3c34c019d504</guid><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 08:02:13 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We were charged with writing 5 "learnings and unlearnings" from our experiences in the course. I wanted to share my takeaways from the class and summarize them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reframing&lt;/strong&gt;: This was probably one of the most valuable tools I took away from the course. I've found a lot of value in being able to look at things from a different angle.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information Interview&lt;/strong&gt;: As a life skill, I personally think that this has started some of the most effective and valuable conversations that I've had recently. Getting in touch with people through information interviewing doesn't only grow my network of people I can reach out to get an insider's perspective and people I can reach out to in the future related to the careers and opportunities I'm interested in.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Odyssey Plan&lt;/strong&gt;: Being able to compile and consolidate my gut feelings and my dreams for the future was a great thought excercise to take something in my head for all this time and put it out into something concrete.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opportunities vs. Offers&lt;/strong&gt;: This was probably the most insightful unlearning that I took away from the course - to treat and frame job inquiries not as offers but as opportunities for a two-sided conversation to learn more about the company, the space, the team, and not just about the potential job offer at hand. More often than not, I've found this to be the most productive way in framing my search for a part-time position next quarter, to invest myself in learning about a more complete perspective of an opportunity rather than the perhaps more narrow view of an offer.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workview vs. Worldview&lt;/strong&gt;: I found tremendous value in articulating my worldview and my workview which I hope to continue revisiting as I progress in life. Trying to succintly decide what means so much to me reminds me of the college application process and that period of introspection. A lot of value comes out of taking a brief step back to see things from a wider angle and this was definitely one of those times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Internet Vigilantism</title><description>&lt;p&gt;There's a new term on the rise that describes the sort of vigilantism in the online world: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;digilantism&lt;/strong&gt; - the act of crowdsourcing efforts via the internet towards the goal of rectifying an injustice deemed morally wrong by an online vigilante group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brought to the forefront of national attention by&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/internet-vigilantism/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">b1edfc68-1375-4be8-a0fa-9f35d0039275</guid><dc:creator>Sherman Leung</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 20:19:22 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;There's a new term on the rise that describes the sort of vigilantism in the online world: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;digilantism&lt;/strong&gt; - the act of crowdsourcing efforts via the internet towards the goal of rectifying an injustice deemed morally wrong by an online vigilante group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brought to the forefront of national attention by the Bostom Marathon Bombings, the topic has resurfaced again due to China's &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-25913472"&gt;flesh-searching engine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="http://explorecourses.stanford.edu/search?view=catalog&amp;amp;filter-coursestatus-Active=on&amp;amp;q=%E2%98%85+CS181W"&gt;CS181W&lt;/a&gt;, this was the topic of our final project + presentation, a case study that combines perspectives from ethics and policy to better understand the ambigious space of internet vigilantism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our final project website + presentation &lt;a href="http://shermanleung.com/cs181w"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>